[音乐响起--字幕精校中--By Persisan]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
DAVID J MALAN：好的。
DAVID J MALAN: All right.
这是 CS50， 哈佛大学的一门介绍
This is CS50, Harvard University's introduction
计算机行业
to the intellectual enterprises of computer science
和编程艺术的一门课程。
and the art of programming.
通常我们都会在这个美丽的桑德斯剧场里
And ordinarily we would all be here on campus in this beautiful Sanders
一起看戏。
Theater together.
不过今年有点不同，
This, of course, is a little bit different this year,
出于很多原因。
for more than one reason.
我们却在哈佛大学的勒布戏剧中心。
But we're here instead in the Loeb Drama Center at Harvard University.
感谢我们的朋友与美国剧目剧团的合作，
Thanks to our friends in collaboration with the American Repertory Theater,
我们有了这个新的空间，甚至包括后面的道具店等设施，
we have this new space, including even such amenities as a prop shop in back,
我们一直在与一个非常有才华的团队合作
where we've been working with an amazingly talented team
一起在暑假期期间为本学期和CS50做准备。
over the course of the summer to prepare for this semester and CS50.
我敢说我们将有一些新的表现方式。
And so I daresay we'll have some new and improved demonstrations along the way.
我们要感谢美国剧目剧团的地主之谊。
So our thanks to our hosts, the American Repertory Theater.
现在我们想唤起一些回忆，至少，
Now we wanted to evoke memories, at least,
关于校园本身的一些图片，特别是
or some imagery of the campus itself, particularly
对于那些本学期无法来这里上课的同学。
for the many of you who could not be here in person this semester.
因此，我们进入了哈佛档案馆，在他们的藏品中
And so we went into the Harvard Archives, where among their collections
有一幅水彩画，是由哈佛大学研究生
was this watercolor painting, painted by a Harvard graduate student
在200年前（1794年）绘制的。
over 200 years ago in the year 1794.
乔纳森·费舍尔（Jonathan Fisher）坐在现在的哈佛广场（Harvard Square）上，
Jonathan Fisher, who sat in what is now Harvard Square,
眺望着哈佛校园最早的建筑。
looking in on some of the earliest buildings of Harvard's campus.
多亏了科技，我们选择这幅相对较小的
And thanks to technology, we took what is a relatively small watercolor
由这位研究生大约在 200 年前画的水彩画，
that this graduate student painted some 200 years ago,
装饰在勒布戏剧中心（Loeb Drama Center）的舞台上。
and now adorns the stage here in the Loeb Drama Center.
所以如果不熟悉的话，我们左手边就是霍尔顿教堂，
So if unfamiliar, we have Holden Chapel here at left,
右边是 Hollis Hall ，是哈佛的本科宿舍之一
Hollis Hall to its right, which is one of the undergraduate dormitories
Harvard Hall 是其中的一间教室
in Harvard Yard, Harvard Hall, which is one of the classroom
然后是 Massachusetts Hall （马萨诸塞大厅），
buildings on campus, and then Massachusetts Hall,
第一年的学生和哈佛校长都在此居住和工作。
where both first years and Harvard's president live and work respectively.
欢迎来到 CS50。
So welcome, then, to CS50.
话说不久之前，
And I can say that not quite as long ago,
也可以说还是很久以前，大约20年前，
but, nonetheless, feels rather long ago, some 20 years ago,
我也在上这个课。
did I take the same class.
但是正如你所知，
But as you know, I myself had some trepidation
在学习 CS50 时，在学习计算机科学时，我也有一些担心。
when it came to studying CS50, when it came to studying computer science.
因为这是一个我不了解的领域。
Because it was a very unfamiliar field.
我上大学时选择了一条让我觉得舒服的发展路线
I had followed a path when I got to college of sticking within my comfort
我以为我会主修政治学
zone, studying government early on, thinking I would major
或者专心于政治。
or concentrate in government.
刚开始我很紧张，直到我鼓起勇气坐在那里，
And it wasn't until I got up the nerve to shop, that is, sit in
坐在 CS50 的课堂上，我意识到实际上这门课很有趣。
on this class CS50, that I realized that homework can actually be fun.
我发现计算机科学和CS50并不是关于编程本身的，
And I found that computer science and CS50 is not about programming per se,
但无论是我们，还是去上这门课的同学，
even though that's how many of us perceive it in high school,
在高中时都是这么认为的。
whether it's us or our classmates taking the class.
但计算机科学其实是关于如何解决问题的艺术。
But it really is about problem solving.
因此它不仅非常适用到
And as such, it's so very applicable not only
计算机科学和工程领域，
to computer science and the engineering fields,
也适合于艺术，人文科学，社会科学，科学及其他领域。
but really to the arts, humanities, social sciences, sciences, and beyond.
因此，如果你也对参加 CS50 这样的课程，
And so if you're feeling a little uncomfortable
感到有点不舒服，
with the idea of taking a class like CS50,
要知道每年几乎有近三分之二参加 CS50 的学生
know that almost every year, nearly two thirds of the students who take CS50
之前从没学过计算机科学课程。
have never taken a computer science course before.
因此，如果你环顾四周，其实大部分同学
So if you look up, down, left, right, right now, odds are more than many
跟你的情况一样。
of the classmates joining you here today are in a very similar position.
你们可以彼此陪伴，一起学习。
You're indeed in very good company.
在课程大纲中，我们强调 CS50 中最重要的一点，
And what's ultimately important in CS50 too, we emphasize, as in the syllabus,
不是在过个过程中你跟别的同学比较
that what ultimately matters in this course is not so much where
而是在结束之时
you end up relative to your classmates, but where you end
跟你自己比较。
up relative to yourself when you began.
确实，考虑到你当前所在的水平，也许
Indeed, taking into account where you currently are, perhaps
你没有基础知识，
with no prior background, and considering
你将在短短的三个月左右的时间内到达
where you will be in just three or so months
最终让自己满意的标准。
is ultimately meant to be the measure of your own success.
为此，我们就从一些过去的小玩意儿里，
And so toward that end, we'll start off this class programming
开始这个课程。
a little something from yesteryear.
这里有一张超级马里奥的图片，还有这些角色要
An image here of Super Mario Brothers and the pyramid
跨过的金子塔砖块。
that the character has to ascend.
我们将使用文本重新创建游戏的一部分，
We'll recreate a portion of this game, albeit using text--
也就是所谓的 ASCII 艺术- 但我们将在课程的
otherwise known as ASCII art-- but we'll do that in just the course's second
第二周完成。
or so week.
这将是你编写的第一个程序。
So this will be among the first programs you write.
然后快速前进，只是几个问题集或编程作业
And then fast forward just several problem sets or programming
在几个星期之后，
assignments later, or several weeks later, too,
你将建立一个在互联网上运行的应用程序，
and you'll be building what we call CS50 Finance, a web
我们称之为 CS50 金融，
application of your very own that runs on the internet,
从第三方服务中抓取近乎实时的股票报价，
pulling down nearly real-time stock quotes from a third party service,
允许你的用户登录注册，以及买卖股票，
allowing your own users to log in and register to buy and sell stocks,
或者说使用虚拟货币。
so to speak, using virtual currency.
因此，在这几个月的课程中，
So over the course of the class's several months,
你将真正地从在马里奥里建造一面金字塔墙
will you go, truly, from building a pyramid in Mario
到构建自己的 Web 应用程序。
to building your very own web application and more,
然后是本课程的最终经验
followed by the course's capstone experience, which
这将是你的最终项目。
will be your very own final project.
但是计算机科学到底是什么？
But what exactly is computer science?
我们认为在第 0 周，即课程的第一周，我们要做的是
What we thought we would do in this week zero, the very first week of the class,
考虑到底什么叫解决问题。
is consider exactly what it means to solve problems.
要我说这就是计算机科学。
And let me propose that this is computer science.
就是解决问题。
This is problem solving.
你有一些输入，就是你关心的你想解决的问题
You have some input, which is the problem you care about
你关心这个问题的解决方案，
that you want to solve, and you care about the solution to that problem,
也就是所谓的输出。
which is the so-called output.
在输入和输出之间是这个黑盒
And in between that input and output is this black box
里面似乎有一种魔力，
of sorts, inside of which is the magic that happens,
一种最终让你能够利用和强迫计算机
the magic that you'll eventually be able to harness and compel computers
去为你解决问题的魔力。
to solve problems for you.
最终，黑盒内部将是你编写的代码。
Inside of that black box, ultimately, is going to be the code that you write.
但我们要开始这样做，我们都
But for us to begin doing that, we all kind of
需要就如何表示这些输入和输出达成一致。
need to agree on how we're going to represent these inputs and outputs.
我们所有人都必须说一种共同的语言。
We all kind of have to speak a common language, so to speak.
可以这么说，我们需要就如何表示这些输入有统一的方法。
And so we need to agree how these inputs are going to be represented.
那么，我们通常如何表示信息呢？
So how might we typically represent information?
好吧，也许最简单的事就是在第一节课的时候
Well, maybe the simplest thing to do at the very first class, whether we're
无论是在线上还是在现场
online or in person, is to take attendance
都要进行考勤，统计一下人数。
or to count the number of people in the room.
你可能会在手上做这种老派的风格，
And so you might do this old school style on your hands
举起一根手指
so as to represent every person in a room
代表房间里的一个人。
with just a finger raised on your hands.
所以我们用手指
So how we might represent information boils down
表示简单的数字信息。
to very simple digits on your hand.
当然，仅用手不能指望你能数到很多数字。
Of course, you can't count very high with just this hand.
实际上，我们正在做的事有一个很好的老派的形容词，
And there's actually a fancy word for what we're doing,
那就是单数记法 ，一根手指代表一个人，
old school here, and that's unary notation-- uno, implying one,
一根手指向上或向下。
or one finger being up or down.
这样看来，你最多可以数五个人。
And so you can count, it would seem, as high as five.
当然，如果我拿出第二手，
And of course, if I bring in a second hand,
我可以数到十，然后事情就变难了。
I can go as high as 10, and then things get a little more difficult.
但这是一个代表信息的系统
But it's a system for representing information
当我们都是小孩的时候经常会使用它。
and it's fairly universal, certainly when we're all quite young.
但是现在我们更倾向于使用更有用的系统。
But you and I tend to use a more useful system.
不只是手上的数字，还有其他种类的数字。
Not just digits on the hand, but other sorts of digits.
也就是你我都知道的十进制数字。
Namely, the decimal digits that you and I know.
所以，这些数字在技术上更多地被称为基数 10 --
So the numbers that are otherwise more technically called base 10--
这只是一种花哨的表述
and that's just a fancy way of describing the fact
我们作为人类实际上通常会使用 10 位数字。
that there's 10 digits that you and I as humans really tend to use typically.
当然，这些数字是从 0 到 9，
Those digits, of course, are zero through nine,
利用这几个数字，我们可以摆出 0
and using these several digits, we can pose numbers like zero
到 9 的数字，还有 10 和 11、12 这样的数字
through nine, but also 10 and 11 and 12, and as high up
想多少有多少。
as we want to go by using multiple digits still.
但是计算机与我们说的语言并不完全相同。
But computers don't really speak the same language as us.
从某种意义上讲，它们比我们人类要简单得多，
They're, in some sense, much simpler than we humans,
即使它们看起来是如此复杂，也如此之快。
even though they seem so complicated or so sophisticated and certainly so fast.
归根结底，这些都是人造设备，
At the end of the day, these are all human-made devices,
而且它们的核心相对简单。
and they're relatively simple at their core.
实际上，即使你不太知道自己在说什么，
In fact, even if you don't quite know what you're saying,
但你至少听说过这种情况，
but you've at least heard this to be the case,
你知道计算机说的是什么语言吗？
what language do you understand computers to speak?
如果不是我们的语言，那计算机会说什么语言，
What language do computers speak, if not the system that you and I use
0 到 9 或十进制？
of zeros through nines or decimal?
Brian，让我们看看谁能回答这个问题？
Brian, could we see who might answer this?
据你所知，计算机使用什么语言系统？
What system do computers use, so far as you've heard,
不论你之前是否参加过CS课。
whether or not you've taken a CS class before?
Keith，我们可以先请你回答吗？
Keith, can we go to you first?
听众：好的。
AUDIENCE: Yeah.
计算机使用二进制。
The computers use binary.
DAVID J MALAN：二进制。
DAVID J MALAN: Binary.
你能详细说明一下吗？
And can you elaborate a little bit?
你所说的二进制是什么意思？
What do you mean by binary?
听众：是零和一。
AUDIENCE: It's zeros and ones.
所以，就像，当我们使用 0 到 9 表示十进制的基数，
So, like, while we use zero through nine for base 10,
他们使用 0 到 1 作为二进制的基数。
they use zero through one for base 2.
DAVID J MALAN：好的，非常正确。
DAVID J MALAN: Yeah, exactly.
因此，计算机使用所谓的二进制系统，表示两个。
So computers use the so-called binary system, bi implying two.
实际上，正如 Keith 所指出的那样，它们仅使用 0 和 1，两个数字。
And they, indeed, only use, as Keith notes, zero and one, two digits.
所以从一方面看，这实际上是令人鼓舞的，
So on the one hand, this is actually pretty encouraging,
你想想看，如果我们只使用两个数字，
because, wow, this is actually a pretty simple system if we're only
这实际上是一个非常简单的系统。
using two of these digits.
但是，当然，如果你只有两个数，
But, of course, if you only have two digits,
我们将如何表示 2 或 3 或 4
how are we going to represent the number two or three or four
还是更大的数字？
or any much larger number?
这看起来像是倒退了。
It would almost seem like a step backwards.
但实际上不是。
But it isn't actually.
而事实证明，这个所谓的系统，或者说以 2 为基数
And it turns out that this so-called system, or base 2--
因为只有两个数字，
two because there's two digits in the vocabulary, otherwise known,
正如 Keith 所说，二进制
as Keith says, as binary--
仅使用 0 和 1，这里还有很多其他命名方式
uses just zeros and ones, and it turns out there's other nomenclature here
我们先不管。
we can toss out.
这些零和一被称为比特。
These zeros and ones are otherwise known as bits.
实际上，比特仅来自两个数字，即二进制数字。
And bits actually derive from just two words, binary digits.
二进制，意味着两种可能性，数字，
Binary, implying two possibilities, digits,
只是屏幕上的符号。
just being symbols on the screen.
因此二进制数字，也就是所谓的比特。
So binary digits, or otherwise known as bits.
而计算机用这些叫做比特的东西来表示二进制。
And computers speak binary using these things called bits.
但这意味着什么，为什么会这样呢？
But what does that mean and why is it the case?
就像，他们为什么不在几十年前就发明计算机
Like, why didn't they invent computers decades ago
只使用 0 到 9，而不是
that just use zero through nine, rather than
想出一个全新的系统让我们去费劲思考，更不要说讨论了？
come up with a whole new system for us to think about, let alone talk about?
那么，归根结底，计算机正在使用什么作为输入？
Well, at the end of the day, computers are using what as their input?
其实只是电。
Really just electricity.
也许我们所有人每天或每隔几天都会对我们的笔记本电脑、台式机或手机
Probably the only thing all of us do every day or every couple of days
做的唯一一件事，就是确保它插着电源，
with our laptop or desktop or phone is either make sure it's still plugged in,
或者给它插上电源，以便为它充电。
or to plug it in so as to charge it.
因此，我们设备的唯一的物理输入
So the only physical input to our devices
就是某种形式的电。
these days is electricity in some form.
我们不必细说什么是电，
And we don't have to get into the nuances of what electricity is,
但我认为它是关于电子流入设备，从而给它充电。
but I think it's about electrons flowing into the device so as to charge it.
因此，对于我们来说，只要知道有一些物理上的输入到我们使用的电脑和手机
So it suffices for our purposes to know that there's
这些设备就足够了。
some physical input to the device, these computers and phones that we use.
就是这样。
But that's it.
因此，如果我们利用这些电力，也许我们
And so if we harness this electricity, maybe we
可以用它来表示信息。
can start to represent information with it.
例如，这是一个灯泡，这是剧院里的旧鬼灯
For instance, here is a light bulb, this old ghost light in the theater here
目前是关闭的。
that's currently off.
但是它具有打开的能力。
But it has the ability to turn on.
我们只需要插上电源或打开开关就可以。
We just need to plug it in or throw on a switch.
如果是这样，
And if that's the case, what's really quite
我们就使用这个灯来打个比方
compelling about the metaphor of using lights
就是这个灯泡，现在是关闭的
is that right now, this light bulb is currently off,
但只要我让电流流动
but as soon as I allow electricity to flow
例如通过插上电源或打开开关，你看，亮了。
as by plugging it in or maybe throwing a switch, now it's, of course, on.
如果我拔下电源插头或关上开关，灯就关了。
And if I unplug it or throw the switch again, it's off.
或者，如果我重新插上，它就会打开。
Or if I plug it back in, it's on.
而这个非常简单的想法的含义
And the implication of this very simple idea
是我们可以使用一个物理设备，例如单个灯泡，
is that we can take a physical device, like a single light bulb,
通过插上或拔下它，我们可以表示信息。
and by plugging it in or unplugging it, we can represent information.
我刚才做了什么？
What did I just do?
我来表示灯泡是开还是关，
I represented the light bulb being off or on,
但我们也可以把关和开叫做其他东西。
but we can just call off and on something else.
我们可以称它们为零和一。
We can call them zeros and ones.
这确实是一个对我们发明计算机的启发
And so this really is the germ of an idea
以及随之而来的二进制系统的使用。
that gave us computers, and with it, their use of the binary system.
如果最终仅有的物理输入是电流，
If, at the end of the day, all they have is physical input as electricity,
那就让我们使用电流来控制和跟踪信息。
well, let's just use that to harness and keep track of information.
当我们想要表示 1 时，让我们给它一点电流，
Let's store a little bit of electricity when we want to represent a one,
当我们想要表示一个 0
and let's let go of that electricity in some sense
时就把电流关上。
when we want to represent a zero instead.
因此，计算机的输入非常简单，
And so because the input to computers is so simple,
我们仅仅使用 0 和 1。
thus gives us the zeros and ones that we now use.
但是，我们似乎为自己制造了一个问题。
But we seem to have created a problem for ourselves.
如果我们只有一个灯泡或一个开关，如果它不亮，
If we only have one light bulb or one switch, if it's off,
它可能为 0 ，如果为开，则可能为 1，
it might be zero, if it's on, it might be a one,
但是我怎么表示一个比 1 大的数字呢？
but how do I count higher than one?
这个问题从根本上仍然存在。
That problem still fundamentally remains.
好吧，我当然可以使用更多的灯泡。
Well, I could, of course, use more light bulbs.
所以让我问一下这个问题。
So let me ask this.
如果我们要使用三个灯泡，我们最多可以表示几？
If we were to use three light bulbs, how high could we count?
因此，使用一个灯泡，我们可以从表示 0 到 1 两种可能性。
So with one light bulb, we can count from zero to one, two possibilities.
但是使用三个灯泡，我们最多可以表示几？
But with three light bulbs, how high could we count?
让我继续在线问这个问题。
Let me go ahead and ask this question here on the screen.
很快你就会看到这个特殊的问题，
In just a moment you'll see on your side this particular question via which
你可以在设备上做出回应。
you can respond on your device.
三个灯泡最多可以表示几？
How high can you count with three light bulbs?
我给你三个灯泡，而不是一个灯泡，每个灯泡都可以打开或关闭。
So instead of one, I give you three, each of which can be on or off.
最多可以表示几呢？
How high can we, perhaps, count?
你将在这个屏幕上看到答案。
So you'll see on the screen here the answers coming in.
有很多人在思考，60％ 人以上回答是 8
We have a lot of folks thinking, 60-plus percent that it's
8 是你可以表示的最大数字。
eight is the highest you can count.
你们中的很多人都认为是 7，有些人
A lot of you think it's seven, and some of you
也有人认为是 3 或者 2。
also think it might be three or two.
这些答案都很有趣。
So that's actually an interesting range of answers.
让我们看看实际可能是什么情况。
And let's see what might actually be the case.
好吧，让我在这里减少到三个灯泡，关闭所有的
Well, let me cut back over to three actual light bulbs here, all of which
灯泡。
are off.
从最简单的开始，我认为，如果我们都打开这些灯泡，
And most naively, I think, if we were to turn these light bulbs on,
如果它们当前代表零，显然，我可以将其打开
if they currently represent zero, obviously, I could turn one on
我们可以认为它表示 1。
and we could call it one.
然后我可以打开第二个，它表示 2，打开第三个，
Then I could turn the second one on and call it two, turn on the third one,
现在三个都启用了，我们可以说现在表示 3。
and now with all three on, we could say now we're representing three.
但这还不是最聪明的做法，如果我们最高
But we're not really being clever enough just yet, if we're only
只是到 3 的话。
counting as high as three.
因为在这个方法中，我只是从左到右打开它们。
Because I'm just turning them on, in this story, left to right.
但是，如果我们更加进一步呢？
But what if we were a little more clever?
也许我们将它们从右到左打开，或者也许我们对它们进行
Maybe we turn them on right to left, or maybe we kind of permuted them
不同的方向的排列？
in different directions?
也就是说，我们不仅考虑灯泡的个数
That is, we took into account not just how many bulbs are on
或有多少根手指，而是
or how many fingers are in the air, but rather the pattern of on
打开和关上的灯泡的排列模式。
and off light bulbs that we've created.
那就让我们来数一下。
So let's just count this up.
我们来有规律地打开一些灯泡，
So let me somewhat systematically turn some of these bulbs on here,
尽管它们是虚拟的。
albeit virtually.
现在可能表示 1 ，现在可能表示 2，现在可能表示 2。
Here might be one, here might be two, here might be three.
但是那样这个事情就结束了。
But then we're kind of done with that story.
那么我们如何才能做得更好呢？
So how might we do it a little better?
好吧，让我们从 0 开始。
Well, let's start again at zero.
这表示 1。
Here might be one.
我们为什么不用这个表示 2 呢？
Why don't we call this two?
为什么不用这个表示 3 呢？
Why don't we call this three?
为什么不用这个表示 4 呢？
Why don't we call this four?
这是 5，6 和 7。
Call this five, this six, and this seven.
如果你现在还看不太懂这个模式，没关系，
Now, it's fine if you didn't quite see what pattern I was following,
但请你相信我，这是一种独特的灯泡模式，
but take my word for it that that was a unique pattern of light bulbs,
一共八次。
eight total times.
我从关闭，关闭，关闭，然后打开，打开，打开。
I started at off, off, off, and I ended at on, on, on.
但是一路下来，3 个灯泡，确实是 8。
But along the way, there were, indeed, eight.
但是我最多能数多少呢？
But how high can I count?
嗯，这取决于你要从哪个数字开始数，
Well, it kind of depends on what number you start counting from,
就像我们到目前为止所做的那样，计算机科学家一直在做。
and just as we thus far have been doing, computer scientists do all the time.
计算机科学家，以及计算机程序，
Computer scientists and, in turn, computer programs,
通常从零开始计数，只是因为它有意义
typically start counting from zero, just because it makes sense
因为当一切都关闭时，你最好将其称为 0。
because when everything is off, you might as well call that zero.
因此，如果我们从零开始计数，那么就有八种可能的模式
So if we start counting at zero, and we have eight possible patterns
我们只是从图片上看到了
that we just saw pictorially, well, that would
让我们数到七。
allow us to count as high as seven.
所以从零到七个，所以七是最大的
So from zero to seven, so seven is the highest
我们可以用三个灯泡数。
we can count with three light bulbs.
正确答案是 7 ，有36％
So those of you who propose that seven was the answer, 36% of you
的回答是正确的。
were indeed correct.
如果你假设我们从 1 开始算，那么 87% 的人回答 8 是对的，
57% of you who said eight are correct if you assume we start counting at one,
很好。
and that's fine.
但是至少在现在的计算机世界中，按照惯例，
But at least in the computing world now, we'll generally, by convention,
从零开始计数。
start counting from zero.
但是你说的很对，有八种这样的可能性。
But you are correct to say that there's eight such possibilities.
好吧，这很好
All right, well, this is all fine and good
用灯泡的模式来代表事物。
to represent things with patterns of light bulbs.
但我们是如何从计算机
But how do we actually now get to the zeros and ones
获取实际的零和一呢？
that a computer is actually using?
计算机的内部到底是什么，
Because what's inside of a computer, at the end of the day,
不是灯泡，而是非常小，微小的开关，
are not light bulbs but tiny, tiny little switches,
数以百万计的小开关，它们可以是打开表示 1 ，关闭表示 0。
millions of little switches that can either be on, or one, or off, or zero.
这些开关被称为晶体管。
Those switches happen to be called transistors.
如今，计算机的确有数百万
And these days computers do have millions
的晶体管可以以不同的模式开启和关闭。
of these things that can be on and off in different patterns.
因此，如果你有能力打开和关闭所有这些开关，那么，
So if you have the ability to turn on and off all of these switches, well,
在使用这些开关时，我们所有人都可以在表示形式上达成共识吗？
what can we all agree on representation when it comes to using those switches?
我们将如何用它们代表信息？
How will we represent information with them?
好吧，美妙的是，我们真的不需要很努力地去思考
Well, wonderfully, we don't really need to think very hard
或者克服我们孩童般的舒适。
or go past our very comfortable roots as kids.
如果我们暂时考虑的不只是零和一，
If we consider for a moment not just zero and one,
而是整个十进制系统（从零到九）
but the whole decimal system, zero through nine,
你们和我都从今天开始。
that you and I all started our day with today.
这个系统是如何工作的？
How does that system work?
嗯，屏幕上的数字是 123。
Well, here on the screen is 123.
所以，你可能会认为是一百二十三，
So yes, you're probably thinking that's one hundred twenty three,
但不完全是。
but not quite.
我在屏幕上显示的只是一种符号的模式
All I've shown on the screen is a pattern
一百二十三， 或者三个数字。
of symbols, 123, or three digits.
而且我们所有人可能都只是本能地在说，
And all of us probably are instinctively just saying, obviously,
这是一百二十三。
it's a hundred and twenty three.
但是可能这么多年来你一直在想
But it's probably been years since you considered
为什么是一百二十三。
why it is one hundred twenty three.
好吧，让我们考虑一下这些数字或符号分别代表什么。
Well, let's consider what each of these digits or symbols represents.
如果你跟我一样，是在长大后才知道最右边的数字是
If you're like me, you grew up learning that the rightmost digit is the ones
个位，中间是十位，左边是百位。
place, the middle is the tens place, the left one is the hundreds place.
那么，我们如何从这三个符号或数字123，
And so how do we get from these three symbols or digits,
到我们所知道的数学概念的一百二十三呢？
123, to the mathematical idea we know as one hundred twenty three?
好吧，我们所有人其实都在一瞬间计算了 100 乘以 1， 加上 10 乘以 2
Well, all of us instantaneously, these days, did 100 times 1 plus 10 times
加上 1 乘以 3，就是 100 + 20 + 3，
2 plus 1 times 3, which, of course, is just 100 plus 20 plus 3,
我们都知道结果是数学上的 123
or the mathematical value we all know as one hundred twenty three.
所以有点循环论证的意思，但只是想提醒大家，
So a bit of a circular argument, but just to remind us
我们是如何从 "123" 到一百二十三的。
how we got from 123 to one hundred twenty three.
好吧，事实证明，在计算机世界中，系统
Well, it turns out that in the world of computers, the system
使用的方法是完全相同的。
they use is exactly, fundamentally the same.
唯一的区别是计算机只能访问零和一，
The only difference is that computers only have access to zeros and ones,
不是零到九。
not zeros through nines.
所以，如果我们现在抽象地考虑，只是在这里表示三个可能的数字，
So if we consider now in the abstract, just three possible digits
我们先考虑一下，为什么这些列是代表
represented here, let's consider for a moment why those columns are places
1、10、100，等等依此类推。
where one, 10, and 100, and so forth.
好吧，为什么会这样呢？
Well, why was that the case?
好吧，事实上，有一种模式
Well, there was a pattern, in fact, and it just
与指数或幂有关。
has to do with exponents or powers.
所以，最右边的一列，技术上，如果我们真的深入细节的话
So the rightmost column, technically, if we really get into the weeds,
是 10 的零次方，如果你还记得的话，
is 10 to the zeroth power, which if you recall,
等于 1，10 的一次方，等于10，
just means one, 10 to the first power, which is just 10,
10 的 2 次方，即 10 的平方，等于100。
and 10 to the second power, or 10 squared, is 100.
但是以这种方式表示好玩的地方
But what's interesting about representing it in this way
是它跳出了 10 本身。
is that it jumps out that 10 is involved.
有 10 个数字，从 0 到 9，所以这些列使用10的基数。
There's 10 digits, zero through nine, so the columns are using this base of 10.
所以你现在也许可以比我更早地考虑到，
So you can perhaps now get even ahead of me
如果在计算机使用的二进制系统中，
here by considering, well, if in the binary system that computers
你只有两个数字，0 和 1，
use, you only have two digits, zeros and ones,
那么唯一要改变的可能就是这些列的意义。
odds are the only thing that's going to change is the meaning of these columns.
现在我们仍然这么替换，因为 2 的 0 次方是 1，
Now we have the ones place still, because 2 to the zero is one,
2 的 1 次方，2 的 2 次方，依此类推。
but then we have 2 to the first, 2 to the second, and so forth.
当然，如果我们只是进行数学运算，
And of course, if we just do out that math,
在计算机使用的二进制世界中，
in the world of binary that computers use,
我们有 1，2，4 等等。
we have the ones place, twos place, fours place, and so forth.
现在我们继续。
And now we're good to go.
尽管我们现在必须在不同的基数系统中思考，
Even though we have to now think in a different base system,
但我们可以开始更正确地计数了。
now we can start counting more properly.
现在我们可以摆脱灯泡的例子了
And now we can move away from the metaphor of light bulbs
考虑一下，如果所有的灯泡都熄灭，
and consider that if all of those light bulbs are off,
同样，我们将再次开始将这些东西视为零。
we're, again, just going to start thinking of those things as zeros.
因此，这将是符号或数字的模式，二进制的形式为 000。
So that would be a pattern of symbols or digits that's 000 in binary.
但是在我们人类的世界里，
But in our human world, the mental math you
你可能会马上心算出来
would probably do now instantaneously after today
好吧，那显然是 4*0 加上 2*0 加上 1*0，
would be, well, that's obviously 4 times 0 plus 2 times 0 plus 1 times 0,
当然，结果是十进制的 0。
or, of course, zero in decimal.
但是，计算机如何表示 1 ？
But how does a computer represent the number one, for instance?
好吧，只是将最右边的位从 0 变成 1，
Well, it's just going to change that rightmost bit from a zero to a one,
或者，比喻来说，它将打开并点亮该开关
or, more metaphorically, it's going to turn that switch on and illuminate
就像我之前所做的那样，那个最右边的灯泡。
that rightmost light bulb just like I did earlier.
我怎么表示 2？
How do I represent two?
二进制是 010。
It's going to be 010 in binary.
我怎么表示 3？
How do I represent three?
这就是跟我们不一样的地方。
This is where we're about to differ.
现在我要打开其中两个开关，
Now I'm putting on two of those switches,
因为我需要在2和1的位置上有一些东西来给我，
because I need something in the twos place and the ones place to give me,
从数学上讲，3。
mathematically, three.
接下来，如果我们继续选择-
Next, if we go ahead and choose--
数到 4，就是 100。
count up to four, that's going to be 100.
如果我要数到 5，那就是 101
if I want to count up to five, that's going to be 101,
6将是 110，最后，数字 7 将是 111。
six is going to be 110, and finally, the number seven is going to be 111.
因此，似乎使用了三位，每个位可以为零或一，
So it would seem that using three bits, each of which can be a zero or one,
是的，你可以用八种不同的方式来排列它们。
yes, you can permute them in eight different ways.
第一位两种可能性乘以第二位的两种可能性乘以第三位的两种可能性，
Two possibilities for the first times two for the second times two
到第三位就有 8 种情况。
for the third gives us eight.
但按照这个数学和从零开始算的传统，
But as per this math and the intuition of starting counting from zero,
我们最多只能数到 7。
we can only count up as high as seven in total.
好吧，让我们继续，然后来个实例。
Well, let's go ahead and actually take this out for a spin.
当我们不只是有，一个灯泡或三个灯泡时，
When we don't have just, say, let's say, one light bulb or three light bulbs,
实际上，我们拥有
we have, actually, the fortune of having like
一整个舞台的灯泡。
a whole stage worth of light bulbs.
舞台上装饰着 64 个灯泡。
64 light bulbs adorn the stage here.
你知道吗？
And you know what?
Sumner，我们可以继续在这里在屏幕上放一个随机数吗？
Sumner, could we go ahead and put up a random number on the screen here?
好吧，所以如果你从视角看这些灯泡，
All right, so if you can see these light bulbs from your perspective,
我们有 8 个灯泡，还有一堆，
we have eight light bulbs plus another bunch of them,
其他的都关闭了。
and all the others are off.
因此，让我们继续问一个问题。
So let's go ahead and ask a question then.
如果这些灯泡现在不仅仅是一个灯泡，或两个或三个，
If these light bulbs now represent not just one light bulb or two or three,
而是多个-在这种情况下，至少有六个灯泡，
but several more-- in this case, at least six light bulbs,
我们实际上得到了什么数？
what value do we actually get?
好吧，让我继续在屏幕上提问，
Well, let me go ahead and put a question on the screen here,
一会儿就把你们弹出来。
which should pop up on yours in just a moment.
现在，你应该在看到了同样的问题。
And you should see now on your end this same question.
用二进制表示，什么数字-
Put in binary terms, what number--
二进制数 110010 表示十进制的什么数？
in decimal, does binary number 110010 represents?
从左到右，二进制数 110010 代表十进制的什么数？
What decimal number does binary number 110010 represent, from left to right?
我们得到了压倒性的回答。
So here we have an overwhelming response.
50 是正确答案。
50 is indeed the correct answer.
为什么呢？
Now why is that?
好吧，如果我转到这里的物理灯泡，让我们
Well, if I go over to the physical light bulbs here, let's
稍微考虑一下实际的情况。
just consider for a moment what the pattern actually is.
这是 1，2，4，8，16、32，
This here is the ones place, the twos place, four, eight, 16, 32,
而且我们可以继续数下去。
and we could keep going.
但这无关紧要，因为它们全都是关闭的。
But it's not going to matter because they're all off.
所以我们有 32 加 16 加 2
So we have 32 plus 16 plus 2, which indeed gives us
得到我们都知道的十进制数字 50。
the number you and I know in decimal as 50.
试想一下，如果我们可以用其他所有灯泡
And just imagine how high we could count with all of the other light bulbs
可以数到多少
as well.
好的。
All right.
我们从电的故事开始。
So we started with the story with electricity.
然后我们转到数字并表示信息，
We then moved on to numbers and representing things,
十进制或二进制。
either in decimal or in binary.
但是我们有点陷入困境，
But we've kind of painted ourselves into a corner,
因为如果我们只有开关或例子中的
because if we only have at our disposal switches or the metaphorical light
灯泡，我们可以认为是零和一，
bulbs, which we can think of as zeros and ones,
看来计算机唯一能做的就是计算。
it would seem that the only things computers can do is compute.
即，充当计算器。
That is, behave as calculators.
实际上，从一开始，这就是计算机的设计宗旨，
And in fact, early on, that's exactly what computers were designed to do,
确实促进了数学计算，否则本来就相当
was really facilitate mathematical calculations that were otherwise quite
对人类而言是乏味或不可能的。
tedious or impossible for humans.
但是，当然，你和我现在正在使用什么，
But, of course, what you and I are using right now,
我们每天在手机，笔记本电脑和台式机上使用的东西更多
what we use every day on our phones and our laptops and desktops is much more
复杂的。
sophisticated.
因此，让我们考虑一台计算机如何不仅能代表数字，
So let's consider how could a computer represent not just numbers,
但是字母。
but letters of the alphabet.
布莱恩，我们可以请这个人吗？
Brian, could we call on someone for this one?
如果你想举起虚拟牌，
If you'd like to raise your virtual hand,
计算机如何去代表一个字母
how could a computer go about representing letters of an alphabet
像英语一样，如果我们能使用的只是开关吗？
like English if, again, all we have at our disposal is switches?
听众：我们可以分配从二进制中得到的数字
AUDIENCE: We can assign the numbers that we're getting from binary
到特定的字母。
to specific letters of the alphabet.
大卫·J·马兰（David J MALAN）：是的。
DAVID J MALAN: Yeah.
我们可以将特定数字以二进制形式分配给字母。
We can assign the specific numbers in binary to letters of the alphabet.
看来，这几乎是我们唯一的选择。
That's pretty much our only option, it would seem.
如果我们只能对这些开关，电灯泡或钻头进行置换，
If we only have the ability to permute these switches or light bulbs or bits,
好吧，我们所有人都必须同意如何以相同的方式表示字母。
well, we just all have to agree how to represent letters in the same way.
现在，对于我们而言，最简单的方法可能是，你知道吗？
Now, maybe the simplest way for us to do this would be, you know what?
我们都同意，大写字母A将成为第一位。
Let's just all agree that a capital A is going to be the number one.
因此，你打开一个灯泡，或表示二进制数字1。
So you turn on one light bulb, or represent the binary number one.
好吧，对于B，我们可以使用第二。
Well, how about for B, we could use the number two.
对于C，我们可以使用数字三。
For C we could use the number three.
D可以是4，依此类推。
D could be four, and so forth.
我们都只需要同意用这种方式给字母编号。
We all just have to agree to number the letters in that way.
但事实证明，人类确实做到了这一点，
But it turns out humans did exactly that,
但与几年前有所不同。
but a little bit differently years ago.
他们之所以做出决定，是因为我们暂时不会参与其中，
They decided for reasons that we won't get into just now,
实际上，大写字母A实际上是
that, actually, the capital letter A is actually
将由你和我知道的65十进制数表示。
going to be represented by the decimal number you and I know as 65.
现在按位形式，看起来像这样。
Now in bitwise form, that's going to look like this.
这就是计算机将要使用的位模式
So this is the pattern of bits that a computer would
用来代表我们现在知道的十进制数字65，
use to represent the decimal number we now know as 65,
现在计算机要做的只是注意什么
and now what the computer is going to do is just be mindful of what
你正在使用的程序类型。
type of program you're using.
所以是的，如果你使用的是计算器或使用Excel之类的工具
So yes, if you're using a calculator or maybe using something like Excel
在运行软件的情况下，要计算数字，
to crunch numbers, well, in that context when running software,
像是进行数值分析的计算器或电子表格程序，
like a calculator or a spreadsheet program doing numerical analysis,
该程序将在计算机的硬件内部看到
the program is going to see inside of the computer's hardware
代表十进制数字65的开关模式。
the pattern of switches that represents the decimal number 65.
而且由于它是在计算器或电子表格的上下文中，
And because it's in the context of a calculator or spreadsheet, what
你（人类）可能会在屏幕上看到字面上的十进制数字65。
you, the human, might see on the screen is literally the decimal number 65.
但是，如果你和我正在使用短信或电子邮件或任何号码
But if you and I are using text messaging or email or any number
我们正在交流的社交媒体应用程序
of social media apps where we're communicating
不是数字形式，而是字母，例如英文字母，
not numerically but in letters, say, English letters,
在这种情况下，你的计算机将足够智能
in that context your computer is going to be smart enough
要知道，代表65的相同位模式
to know, well, that same pattern of bits that represents 65,
在短信或电子邮件等中
in the context of a text message or in an email or the like
实际上代表大写字母A。因此模式是相同的。
actually represents the capital letter A. So the pattern is the same.
表示是相同的。
The representation is the same.
但是上下文是不同的。
But the context is what differs.
人类几年前想出的系统，将65映射到A，将66映射到B，
And the system that humans came up with years ago that maps 65 to A, 66 to B,
67到C，称为ASCII，美国标准
67 to C, is called ASCII, the American Standard
信息交换代码。
Code for Information Interchange.
这只是意味着存在一个定义明确的映射，
And that just means that there is a well-defined mapping that a bunch
几十年前的人类决定为了绘制字母表中的字母-
of humans decades ago decided on, in order to map letters of the alphabet--
在这种情况下为英语
English in this case--
到以65开头的数字。
to numbers starting with 65.
对于标点符号，小写字母也有一个完整的映射，
And there's a whole mapping, too for punctuation, for lowercase letters,
等等。
and the like.
因此，假设你确实收到了一条包含以下内容的短信：
So given that, suppose that you did receive a text message containing
一种位模式，或者实际上只是一个十进制数字序列
a pattern of bits, or, really, just a sequence of decimal numbers that
碰巧是这个。
happened to be this.
72、73、33。
72, 73, 33.
假设你收到一条包含这些数字模式的短信。
Suppose that you received a text message containing these patterns of numbers.
72、73、33。
72, 73, 33.
你可能会收到什么消息？
What message might you have just received?
让我继续，在这里拉起简短的图表
Let me go ahead and pull up the abbreviated chart here
仔细考虑你收到的消息。
to consider exactly what message you've received.
72、73、33。
72, 73, 33.
萨姆纳，我们可以继续抛出同样的三个字母的单词吗？
And Sumner, could we go ahead and throw this same three-letter word
在灯上？
on the lights?
如果你想按位查看它，可以这么说，
If you'd like to see it in bitwise form, so to speak,
现在它也将出现在这些灯泡上。
it will appear here on these light bulbs now as well.
这代表什么模式？
What pattern does this represent?
兰纳姆，我们可以去找你吗？
Lanham, can we go to you?
听众：HI带有感叹号，对吗？
AUDIENCE: That would be HI with an exclamation point, correct?
DAVID J MALAN：是的，确实如此，带有感叹号。
DAVID J MALAN: Yeah so it's indeed HI with an exclamation point.
回想起来，现在可能很容易
And it's probably pretty easy now, in retrospect,
可以理解，是的，72和73分别是H和I。
to glean that, yes, the 72 and the 73 were H and I respectively.
但是Lanham也指出了这个图表中没有的感叹号，
But Lanham also noted the exclamation point, which isn't in this chart,
但是对于每个点点，都有一个定义明确的映射
but per the dot dot dots, there is a well-defined mapping
对于我们可能关心的所有字母。
for all of the letters of the alphabet that we might care about.
因此，HI可能比其他方法更明显。
And so HI is perhaps more obvious than the other.
那33，我们需要一个更大的图表。
That 33, we need a bigger chart.
因此，如果你实际使用计算机
And so if you actually go on your computers
现在到asciichart.com，asciichart.com，你将
now to asciichart.com, asciichart.com, you'll
看到这样的东西。
see a little something like this.
尽管你也可以只使用google ASCII进行搜索
Though you can also just google ASCII in general
并获得相同图表的副本。
and get copies of the same chart.
你会在这里看到H的确是72，我的确是73，
You'll see here that H is indeed 72, I is indeed 73,
但是如果我们向左看，显然33是一个感叹号。
but if we look to the left, 33 is, apparently, an exclamation mark.
而且，你只会知道查找或只是拥有
And you would only know that by having looked it up or just having
提交给内存。
committed it to memory.
但是你和我使用的计算机以及你和我使用的电话仅
But the computers you and I use and the phones you and I use just
内在地知道这一点。
know this intrinsically.
确实，这就是它们的编程方式。
That's, indeed, how they're programmed.
但事实证明，我们也应该考虑
But it turns out, too, that we should consider
我们现在使用多少个零和一个
just how many zeroes and ones we're using now
分别代表72、73和33
to represent the 72, the 73, and the 33.
因此，让我们最后一次查看二进制表示形式，
So let's look for one last time at the binary representation, which,
根据灯泡，这里是这些位模式。
as per the light bulbs, are these patterns of bits here.
因此，当你收到朋友发来的短信说HI！
So when you receive a text message from a friend saying HI!
HI感叹号，总的来说，
H-I exclamation point, in all caps, you're
从技术上讲，它接收比特模式，某种频率，
technically receiving a pattern of bits, some kind of frequency,
如果是无线的，则表示这种位模式。
if it's wireless, that represents this pattern of bits.
通常，这些天的计算机使用八位
And typically, computers these days use eight bits
代表每个这些字符。
to represent each of those characters.
ASCII首次出现时，通常
When ASCII first came out, they typically
出于效率考虑，只使用了7个，因为当时的空间太昂贵了。
used seven for efficiency reasons, because space was expensive back then.
但是在这里我们使用了八个，实际上，这就是现在
But here we used eight, and, indeed, that's now
以八的倍数表示字符时的规范。
the norm when it comes to representing characters in multiples of eight.
所以我们这里有八位，这里有八位，这里有八位，
So we have eight bits here, eight bits here, eight bits here,
这意味着要收到消息HI！你正在发送或接收24位
which means to receive the message HI! you are sending or receiving 24 bits
全部的。
total.
坦白说，现在位不是一个非常有用的度量单位，
Now, frankly, bits are not a very useful unit of measure,
通常是因为它们很小。
typically, because they're so small.
只是零或一。
Just a zero or a one.
但是这些八位模式中的每一个实际上
But each of these patterns of eight bits, actually
如果可以的话，有一个词汇词，即字节。
have a vocabulary word, if you will, which is bytes.
而且很可能，我们所有人都在某些情况下使用了这个术语，
And odds are, all of us have used this term in some context,
但通常以兆字节甚至千兆字节为背景。
but generally in the context of megabytes or even gigabytes.
确实，当你最近谈论文件的大小时，
Indeed when you talk about the sizes of your files these days,
你是以某种形式的字节（百万字节或十亿字节）说话。
you're speaking in bytes in some form, either million or billion bytes.
但是，这些字节中的每个字节都非常简单地由八个零和一的模式组成。
But each of those bytes, quite simply, is a pattern of eight zeros and ones.
因此，实际上，如果我们可以使用多达64个灯泡，
So, in fact, if we have as many as 64 bulbs at our disposal,
那是64除以8。
that's 64 divided by 8.
那是八个字符。
That's eight characters.
因此，似乎我们可以在此阶段进行拼写，即使是八个字母的单词-
So it would seem we could spell on this stage, even an eight-letter word--
萨姆纳（Sumner），如果我们可以随机输入一个八个字母的单词，
if, Sumner, we could put up a random eight-letter word,
我们现在要跟上
that we'll keep up now--
你现在可以从左向右拼写吗？
can you now spell from left to right, your left
在你的右边，是一个八个字母的单词，使用的是ASCII码系统。
to your right, an eight-letter word using the system known as ASCII.
但是，当然，我们在这里有些偏见，
But, of course, we're being a little bit biased here,
因为ASCII是美国信息交换标准代码。
as ASCII is the American Standard Code for Information Interchange.
当然，在典型的美国英语键盘上，肯定会有更多的字符，
And on a typical US English keyboard, there's more characters, certainly,
而不是大写字母，例如A到H和I。
than uppercase letters, like A through H and I.
还有一些标点符号和一些数字，但也有很多
There's also some punctuation and some numbers, but there's also quite a bit
也失踪了。
missing as well.
你们在世界上其他任何地方的人，
And any of you who are elsewhere in the world, odds are,
会发现使用这样的键盘特别容易造成限制或沮丧。
would find using a keyboard like this especially limiting or frustrating.
这是为什么？
Why is that?
ASCII似乎缺少了什么？
What seems to be missing from ASCII?
好吧，让我在这里问另一个问题。
Well, let me ask this one other question here.
如果我们确实使用ASCII，因此我们给自己八位或一个字节，
If we do use ASCII, and we therefore give ourselves eight bits or one byte,
我们实际上可能会显示多少个不同的字符
how many different characters could we potentially actually display, actually
代表？
represent?
因此，在屏幕上，你现在应该会看到此问题。
So on your screen, you should see this question now.
你可以用8位表示多少个符号？
How many symbols can you represent with eight bits?
最终，这实际上说明了
And this speaks to, really, at the end of the day, how
许多字母加上标点符号，
many letters of the alphabet plus punctuation,
加上大写和小写字母，计算机可以支持ASCII还是真的支持？
plus uppercase and lowercase, can ASCII, or really, can computers support?
好吧，似乎有72％的人认为答案是256。
Well, it looks like 72% or so of you think that the answer is 256.
确实可以代表256种可能性。
And it is indeed the case that you can represent 256 possibilities.
为什么？
Why?
你实际上可以进行数学计算。
You can actually do out the math.
如果你有八位，每位可以是零或一，
If you've got eight bits, each of which can be a zero or a one,
这意味着你有两种可能性，
that means you have two possibilities for the first,
第二次乘以两次，两次乘以两次。
times two possibilities for the second, times two times two times two.
恰好是2到八分之一，即256。
That happens to be 2 to the eighth, or 256.
如果那不是立即显而易见的话，那很好
It's fine if that's not immediately obvious,
但是如果你确实有8位，而每位可以是两个值之一，
but if you do have eight bits, each of which can be one of two values,
你可以想出256种可能性。
you can come up with 256 possibilities.
在这种情况下，那些听到提示说答案为255的人，
Those of you who chimed in to say that the answer is 255 in this case,
是错的，只是因为现在我们在谈论总数
are wrong, only because now we're talking about the total number
模式，实际上是256。
of patterns, which is indeed 256.
但是我们可以用八位或八个灯泡表示的最大值
But the highest value we could represent with eight bits or eight light bulbs,
看来确实是255。
it would seem to be, indeed, 255.
那是因为我们可以置换所有不同的模式。
And that's because of all of the different patterns we can permute.
但是，现在让我向观众们提一个问题。
But let me open the question to the audience now.
为什么美式英语键盘会特别受限制，
Why might a US English keyboard be especially limiting,
反过来，为什么ASCII真的不太合适
and in turn, why is ASCII really not quite appropriate
在表达人类语言时，
when it comes to representing human language,
即使这是几年前开始的计算机？
even though this is what computers began with years ago?
ASCII缺少什么？
What is missing from ASCII?
为什么总共256种可能性不够？
Why might 256 total possibilities not be sufficient?
凯文，我们可以去找你吗？
Kevin, can we go to you?
听众：好的。
AUDIENCE: Sure.
我的意思是，一方面，我没有其他语言的很多口音。
I mean, for one thing, missing a lot of the accents in other languages.
但是，如果你只考虑亚洲语言，
But if you just consider, like, Asian languages,
超过256个字符。
there are a lot more than 256 characters.
大卫·J·马兰（David J MALAN）：好的。
DAVID J MALAN: Exactly.
所以我们不仅缺少重音符号
So not only are we missing accented characters
你可能需要某些语言的版本，
that you might need in some languages, we're
还缺少亚洲语言中可能需要的字符，
also missing the characters that you might need in Asian languages,
像阿拉伯语之类的语言。
in languages like Arabic and the like.
我们人类可以使用更多的方式以印刷形式进行交流
There are way more symbols that we humans use to communicate in print
和电子方式超过256。
and electronically than 256.
英文，我们可以轻松安装此键盘，
English, we can get away with fitting into this keyboard,
但是一旦我们介绍了类似这些字符的东西，
but not once we introduce things like these characters,
更不用说其他符号了。
let alone other symbols as well.
事实证明，这些天来我们人类还有其他要说的话
And it turns out there's other things we humans like to say these days
并使用流行的字符来表达，即
and express using characters that have come into vogue, which is, namely,
这些东西。
these things.
可能是今天某个时候
Odds are, probably sometime today you have
在此处发送或接收这些东西之一，也称为表情符号。
sent or received one of these things here, otherwise known as an emoji.
现在，即使这些表情符号看起来像图片，它们也看起来像图像-
Now, even though these emojis look like pictures, they look like images--
从技术上讲，它们是在计算机中实现的方式
and they are, technically-- the way they're implemented in computers
实际上是零和一的模式。
is actually as patterns of zeros and ones.
这些实际上只是字母（表情符号字母）中的字符。
These are actually just characters in an alphabet, the emoji alphabet.
也就是说存在一些零和一的模式
Which is to say there's some pattern of zeros and ones
代表这些面孔中的每一个面孔，以及许多其他表情符号
that represents each one of these faces, and the many other emojis that
时下存在。
nowadays exist.
这是因为多年来，世界已经从ASCII过渡，
And this is because the world has transitioned over the years from ASCII,
它只使用了七个，在某种意义上，
which only used seven, and in some sense,
总共八位代表所有可能的字符，
eight bits total to represent all possible characters,
使用8个或16个或24个甚至32个。
to using either eight or 16 or 24 or even 32 .
如今，有一个名为Unicode的系统，人类已经出现了
Bits nowadays there's a system called Unicode, which humans have come up
不仅支持英语，还支持所有人类语言，
with that support not only English, but also all of the human languages,
是理想的目标，无论是印刷形式还是电子形式都是目标。
is the aspirational goal, both written in print or electronically is the goal.
除此之外，这就是说我们可以代表这样的事情。
And in addition to that, this is to say we can represent things like this.
因此，这就是充满喜悦的眼泪的面孔。
So this is the so-called face with tears of joy.
从去年开始，满脸欢乐的眼泪，
And this face of tears of joy, as of last year,
是通过短信，电子邮件发送的最受欢迎的表情符号，
was the most popular emoji sent via text messages, emails,
社交媒体等。
social media, and the like.
但是到最后，你所收到的一切
But at the end of the day, all you're receiving
就像键盘上的键一样。
is, like, a key on a keyboard.
因此，实际上，你不会知道它。
So, in fact, you wouldn't know it to look at it.
但实际上，代表此面孔的十进制数字
But in fact, the decimal number representing this face
含着喜悦的眼泪恰好是128,514。
with tears of joy happens to be 128,514.
因此，就凯文而言，不仅要代表某些人类语言，
So to Kevin's point, to represent not only certain human languages,
但肯定这些表情符号，我们需要超过256个字符
but certainly these emojis, we need way more than 256 characters
因此我们不仅可以使用8位，还可以使用16或24或32。
so we can use not just eight bits, but 16 or 24 or 32.
现在有很多可能性。
That's a huge amount of possibilities now.
实际上，现在，要真正从这些事情中获得乐趣，
In fact, now, to really take the fun out of these things,
如果你带着喜悦的眼泪收到或发送这张脸，
if you receive that face with tears of joy or send it,
从技术上讲，你只是发送一种看起来像这样的位模式。
you're technically just sending a pattern of bits that looks like this.
这就是引擎盖下所有的一切，
That's all that's going on underneath the hood,
每次你使用这些东西时。
every time you use these things.
好的。
All right.
因此，我们再次开始用电。
So we started again with electricity.
然后，我们代表数字。
We then represented numbers.
现在我们可以代表字母，甚至
Now we have the ability to represent letters and even
表情符号形式的情绪。
emotions in the form of emojis.
那里还有什么？
What else is there out there?
好吧，表情符号本身，当然，至少我们已经看过了，
Well, the emojis themselves, of course, at least the ones we've looked at,
本质上是图画。
are pictorial in nature.
这就引出了一个问题，一台计算机如何
And so that invites the question, how does a computer
代表颜色之类的东西？
represent things like color?
就像，那张充满欢乐的眼泪的脸上充满了黄色。
Like, that face with tears of joy had a lot of yellow in it.
那么，黄色或任何颜色如何在计算机中表示出来呢？
So how is yellow or any color, for that matter, represented in a computer?
好吧，让我再次问听众。
Well, let me ask the audience again.
如果你拥有的全部是零，零和一，
If all you have at your disposal is bits, zeros and ones,
正如人类需要同意如何表现颜色一样，
and we just as humans need to agree how to represent colors,
一种可能是什么？
what might be one possibility?
不一定是答案。
It doesn't need to be the answer.
但是，如果你是第一次设计，你的本能是什么？
But what might your own instinct be if designing this for the first time
你自己？
yourself?
现在计算机怎么能代表颜色？
How might a computer represent colors now?
亚斯敏，你怎么看？
Yasmin, what do you think?
听众：你希望成员使用不同的颜色和形状
AUDIENCE: You would like members to different colors and shapes
并做同样的系统。
and just do the same system.
DAVID J MALAN：好的，是的。
DAVID J MALAN: Yeah, exactly.
完美的直觉。
Perfect instincts.
你只需将数字分配给不同的颜色，
You would just assign numbers to the different colors,
我们都只需要就该映射的实际含义达成共识。
and we all just have to agree on what that mapping is actually going to be.
事实证明，有不同的方法可以做到这一点。
So it turns out there's different ways to do this.
而且，如果你中的任何人具有艺术性，并以数字方式使用Photoshop或类似工具，
And if any of you are artistic and use Photoshop or the like digitally,
你可能熟悉RGB，红色，绿色，蓝色等首字母缩写词。
you're probably familiar with acronyms like RGB, red, green, blue.
但是还有其他首字母缩写词和其他方式
But there are other acronyms and other ways
实施Yasmin的想法，我们以某种方式将其映射
to implement Yasmin's idea where we just somehow map
零和一为实际颜色。
zeros and ones to actual colors.
好吧，RGB恰好代表红色，绿色和蓝色。
Well, RGB just happens to represent red, green, and blue.
这是人类几年前想出的一个系统，说，你知道吗？
And this is a system humans came up with years ago that says, you know what?
我们实际上可以得到彩虹的每种颜色
We can actually get every color of the rainbow
基本上是将一些红色，绿色和蓝色的光混合在一起。
by mixing together some amount of red and green and blue light, essentially.
因此，这引发了一个问题，好吧，我们如何表示红色的数量，
So that just invites the question, well, how do we represent the amount of red,
我们如何表示绿色的数量，以及我们如何
how do we represent the amount of green, and how do we
代表蓝色的数量？
represent the amount of blue?
正如Yasmin所说，我们还有一些可用的工具。
And we have, as Yasmin says, bits at our disposal.
因此，我们只需要决定如何执行此操作即可。
So we just have to decide how to do this.
因此，假设我们收到了一种位模式，即72、73、33，
So suppose we receive a pattern of bits, that 72, 73, 33 again,
但是这次不是电子邮件。
but this time it's not an email.
它不在短信中。
It's not in a text message.
这是在Photoshop中打开的文件的上下文中。
It's in the context of a file that I've opened in Photoshop.
好像我打开了一张照片，有人
So it's as though I've opened up a photograph that someone
发送给我，我想进行一些编辑，我看到这种数字模式，
sent me and I want to do some editing and I see this pattern of numbers,
或位。
or, in turn, bits.
好吧，在这种情况下代表什么？
Well, what is that representing in this case?
在电子邮件或短信中，它仍然是HI！
In the context of an email or a text message, it's still HI!
但是在Photoshop或Instagram的背景下
But in the context of Photoshop or Instagram
或任何围绕图像的内容，
or anything that is oriented around images,
它实际上将代表一定数量的红色，一定数量的绿色，
it's actually going to represent some amount of red, some amount of green,
一些蓝色。
some amount of blue.
正如我们之前发现的，总数
And as we discovered earlier, the total number
你可以用8位表示的可能性恰好是256。
of possibilities you can represent with eight bits happens to be 256.
如果我们从零开始计数，则可以代表的最大值是255。
The highest value you can represent is 255 if we start counting from zero.
所以这就是说这三个数字
So this is to say that each of these three numbers
是介于0到255之间的数字。
is a number between zero and 255.
所以72感觉像是中等数量的红色，73感觉像是中等数量的绿色，33
So 72 feels like a medium amount of red, 73 is like a medium amount of green, 33
有点蓝。
is a little bit of blue.
如果将这三种颜色组合起来，则八位加八
And if you combine those three amounts of color, eight bits plus eight
位加8位，总共使用24位，
bits plus eight bits, using 24 bits total,
用前三分之一表示红色，后三分之一表示绿色，
using the first third to represent redness, the second third greenness,
结果是三分之一到三度发蓝，
and the third third blueness, you get, it turns out,
像这样的一个点，一个黄色的点。
a dot that looks like this, a yellow dot.
因此，当表情符号显示在屏幕上时，
And so, indeed, that emoji, when it's being displayed on the screen,
是计算机解释的结果-
is the result of the computer interpreting--
128,514的值是知道的，哦，这就是表情符号
the 128,514 value is knowing oh, that's the emoji
带着喜悦的眼泪。
with the face of tears of joy.
但是当涉及到在屏幕上显示信息时，
But when it comes to displaying the information on your screen,
现在你的计算机将使用不同的位模式
now your computer is going to be using different patterns of bits
控制屏幕上点的颜色。
to control the colors of the dots on the screen.
这个词你可能已经知道了。
And this term you might already know.
这些天，你和我在计算机屏幕甚至电视上看到的圆点
The dots you and I see on our computer screens or even TVs these days
被称为像素。
are called pixels.
它们是代表一些颜色的微小小方块
They're tiny little squares that represent some color
例如这里的黄色。
such as this yellow one here.
你实际上可以在某些情况下看到它们。
And you can actually see them in some contexts.
如果我继续前进，用喜悦的眼泪将同一张脸抬起并放大一点，
If I go ahead and pull up the same face with tears of joy and zoom in a bit,
再放大一点，实际上再放大一点，
zoom in a bit more, and really zoom in a bit more,
现在你实际上可以看到我们所谓的像素化。
now you can actually see what we call pixelation.
很有可能，你已经在Facebook，Instagram，
And odds are, you have seen this on Facebook, Instagram,
无论你在什么地方调整尺寸或编辑不太合适的照片
wherever you might be resizing or editing photos that don't quite
有足够的分辨率。
have enough resolution.
图像的分辨率就是那里的像素或点数
The resolution of an image is just how many pixels or dots there
是水平和垂直的。
are horizontally and vertically.
因此，如果你真正放大图像，最终将看到这些像素。
So if you really zoom in on an image, you'll eventually see those pixels.
这就是说，即使在这张放大的笑脸中，
And this is to say that even in this zoomed-in happy face,
有大量的黄点和一大堆
there's a huge number of yellow dots and a whole bunch
黑色，灰色和棕褐色的点也是如此
of black and gray and brownish dots as well
构成了这个非常彩色的图像。
that compose this very colorful image.
这样一来，你就可以看到它们，现在每个点都可以看到，
And so you can see them in that case, and every one of those dots now,
我声称一个像素正在使用24位或3个字节。
a pixel, is using, I claim, like 24 bits or three bytes.
现在，你可以想象，可能有数百个点
Now, you can imagine, there's probably what, hundreds, maybe thousands of dots
在该图像中，如果我们缩小并再次查看所有图像。
in that image if we zoom out and look at all of them again.
因此，如果这些点或像素中的每一个都是三个字节，
So if every one of those dots or pixels is three bytes,
这就是为什么我和你拍照的原因
this is why the photographs you and I take
以及你和我从互联网上下载的图像
and the images you and I download from the internet
通常通常不以字节为单位来度量，而是以千字节为单位，
are typically measured not even in bytes, per se, but in kilobytes,
成千上万个字节，或者兆字节上百万个字节，
for thousands of bytes, or megabytes for millions of bytes,
或者如果是视频文件，则可能会更大，数十亿或千兆字节。
or if it's a video file, it might get even bigger, billions, or gigabytes.
但这就是引擎盖下发生的全部事情。
But that's all that is happening underneath the hood.
我们只是以这种方式表示信息。
We're just representing information in this way.
好吧，现在让我问一个后续问题。
Well, let me ask a follow up question now.
如果我们现在有了Yasmin，代表了颜色，
If we've now, thanks to Yasmin, represented colors,
进而是图像，因为所有图像都是一个像素网格。
and in turn, images, because all an image is is a grid of pixels.
你采用Yasmin提出的相同原则，
You take the same principle Yasmin proposed,
你代表一个点的每种颜色，并且有一堆点
where you represent each color of a dot and you have a whole bunch of dots that
给我们提供图像，你如何建议计算机代表视频文件？
gives us images, how would you propose computers represent video files?
同样，即使你不知道答案，怎么办
Again, even if you don't know the answer, how might
一台计算机现在仅使用位来表示视频文件
a computer represent video files now using, again, only bits
在他们的处置？
at their disposal?
谁会喜欢这个？
Who might like to field this one?
计算机如何代表视频？
How might a computer represent a video?
贾斯汀，你怎么看？
Justin, what do you think?
听众：我-也许只是在迅速改变自己的口感？
AUDIENCE: I-- maybe just, like, rapidly changing the bites?
DAVID J MALAN：只是在迅速改变话题。
DAVID J MALAN: Just rapidly changing the bites.
我听说-你能详细说明一下吗？
I hear-- can you elaborate a little bit?
改变口语是什么意思？
What do you mean by changing the bites?
听众：就像快速改变单个像素的RGB一样，
AUDIENCE: Like rapidly changing the RGB of individual pixels--
大卫·J·马兰（David J MALAN）：好的。
DAVID J MALAN: Exactly.
听众：-匹配那秒钟的图像
AUDIENCE: --to match the image of that second
视频或视频的一部分。
of the video or portion of the video.
DAVID J MALAN：完美。
DAVID J MALAN: Perfect.
因此，如果你考虑使用像手机这样的矩形屏幕，
So if you think about, like, the rectangular screen that is your phone,
或笔记本电脑或台式机显示器（如果你只是
or your laptop, or your desktop monitor, if you just
每秒更改一次这些点的颜色
keep changing the colors of those dots once per second
或每秒一整堆的时间，我们将
or a whole bunch of times per second, we'll
感觉到屏幕上确实有运动，所以是视频。
get the illusion that there's actually motion on the screen, ergo video.
所以说真的，从某种意义上讲，视频只是一堆图像，
So really, a video, in some sense, it's just a whole bunch of images,
达到Yasmin的定义，可以非常迅速地在屏幕上飞行。
to Yasmin's definition, flying across the screen really quickly.
这样你就可以看到这种甚至古老的学校风格。
And so you can see this even old school style.
例如，让我继续并在屏幕上打开
For instance, let me go ahead and open up on my screen
代表翻书的简短视频。
a short video that represents a flipbook.
因此，你可能在小时候就已经成为其中之一，或者你可能是你的老师
So you might have made one of these as a kid or maybe your teacher
或至少在某个地方亲眼看到了它们。
did or you saw them, at least, in person somewhere.
如果要拿一大堆纸和钉书钉
Where if you take a whole bunch of pieces of paper and staple
或以某种方式将它们剪裁在一起，绘制大量图片，所有这些
or clip them together in some way, draw a whole lot of pictures, all of which
在每一页上相似但略有不同，
are similar but slightly different on each page,
你可以创建动画，或者实际上是视频。
you can create an animation, or, really, a video.
这就是纯电子世界中的所有视频。
And this is all a video is in a purely electronic world.
即使恰好实现了
Even though this happens to be implemented
在纸上，计算机世界会发生什么
in paper, what happens in the computer world
确实只是整个图像序列
is indeed just a whole sequence of images
以一定的速度飞过屏幕。
flying across the screen at some rate.
这就是实际上为我们提供了你我今天所知道的视频文件的原因。
And that's what actually gives us the video files that you and I know today.
而且还有更多的兔子洞我们可以下去。
And there's even more rabbit holes we can go down.
例如，你将如何表现音乐？
For instance, how might you represent music?
好吧，音乐可以用不同的方式表现出来。
Well, music, could be represented, gosh, in different ways.
例如，如果你弹钢琴，
Like, if you play the piano, for instance, you
可能知道有些音符，例如A到G。
might know that there are notes, like A through G.
但是也有尖锐的东西和平坦的东西等等。
But there's also sharps and flats and so forth.
但是你知道吗？
But you know what?
也许我们只需要一个数字来表示每个可能的注释。
Maybe we just need a number to represent each of those possible notes.
也许我们也可以使用其他数字，
And maybe also we could use another number,
就像图像使用多个数字来表示点一样，
just like images use multiple numbers to represent dots,
我们可以用数字来代表歌曲中的音符，
we could use a number to represent the notes in a song,
而且还有一个数字代表该音符的持续时间。
but also another number to represent the duration of that note.
你应该听到该音符多少秒，毫秒或节拍。
How many seconds or milliseconds or beats should you hear that note for.
因此，你也可以提出其他公式，
So you could come up with other formulations, too,
但实际上，音乐可以在计算机世界中量化
but music, really, can be quantized in the world of computers
只是一小部分信息。
into just small pieces of information.
只要你我同意如何代表它，
And so long as you and I agree on how to represent it,
这些都是这样的。
that's how these things all work.
如果你曾经想知道为什么会有JPEG，PNG，GIF和Word
And if you've ever wondered why there are JPEGs and PNGs and GIFs and Word
文档和Excel文件以及所有这些不同的文件格式或文件
documents and Excel files and all of these different file formats or file
计算机上的扩展名，这些文件扩展名或格式仅
extensions on computers, those file extensions or formats just
代表一大堆人同意
represent a whole bunch of humans agreeing
如何在文件中存储零和一的模式
how to store patterns of zeros and ones in a file
这样，当这些零和一被加载到计算机中进行显示时
so that when those zeros and ones are loaded into a computer for display
或为了解释，它知道这些模式代表什么。
or for interpretation, it knows what those patterns represent.
图像的表示方式略有不同，
Images are represented slightly differently,
声音和视频的表示方式略有不同，
sound and video are represented slightly differently,
但是一天结束时都是零和一。
but it's all zeros and ones at the end of the day.
这就是说，只要我们都同意，最好是在世界范围内，
So this is all to say, so long as we all agree, ideally around the world,
如何表示信息，现在我们可以表示问题的输入
how to represent information, now we can represent inputs to problems
并希望解决问题并获得产出。
and hopefully solve problems and get outputs.
因此，所有这些问题仍然存在于解决问题的过程中，或者实际上是在计算机科学领域，
So all that remains in problem solving, or really, computer science broadly,
就是要看这个黑匣子的内部，并考虑如何进行输入，
is to look inside of this black box and to consider how you take inputs,
无论是数字，字母，图像，视频，声音，
whether it's numbers, letters, images, video, sound,
并将其转换为实际的解决方案。
and convert them into actual solutions.
所以在这个黑匣子的内部，我们通常会
And so inside of this black box is what we would typically
描述为算法。
describe as algorithms.
算法是解决问题的分步说明。
Algorithms are step by step instructions for solving problems.
他们甚至不必参与计算机。
They don't even have to involve computers.
我们人类只需遵循别人的指令就可以执行算法。
We humans can execute algorithms just by following someone else's instructions.
如果你曾经按照食谱制作食谱，
If you've ever prepared something from a cookbook, following a recipe,
你正在逐步执行算法。
you are executing an algorithm step by step.
但是不像很多食谱或者不像很多
But unlike a lot of recipes or unlike a lot
人类相互之间的指示，
of instructions that we humans give to each other,
计算机中没有歧义的余地。
there's no room for ambiguity in computers.
由机器实施的计算机算法，
Computers' algorithms, when implemented by machines,
他们不仅必须正确，所以
they really have to be not only correct so
得到你所关心的正确输出，
that you get the right outputs that you care about,
但它们也需要精确。
but they also need to be precise.
你需要如此精确，因为与我们人类不同的是，
You need to be ever so precise, because unlike we humans who can kind of like
在两行之间阅读，是的，我明白了你的意思，
read between the lines and, yeah, I get what you mean,
电脑将带你从字面上看。
computers are going to take you literally.
因此，在对计算机进行编程（即翻译算法）时，
And so when programming a computer, that is, translating an algorithm,
逐步说明，将其翻译成计算机可以理解的某种语言，
step by step instructions, into some language the computer understands,
你有责任确保计算机不会误解你的意思
the onus is on you to make sure that the computer cannot misinterpret what you
想。
want.
因此，让我们考虑一种这样的算法。
So let's consider one such algorithm.
因此，在我们所有的手机（无论是iOS还是Android或类似设备）上，
So on all of our phones, whether iOS or Android or the like,
你有一些联系人应用程序。
you have some contacts application.
该联系人应用程序可能存储了你所有的朋友
And that contacts application's probably storing all of your friends
以及家人和同事，可能是按字母顺序。
and family members and colleagues, probably alphabetically.
也许是名字，也许是姓氏，或者
Maybe by first name, maybe by last name, or however
你已经整理好了该设备。
you've organized that device.
好吧，这种情况的旧版本
Well, the old school version of this happens
变成纸质的，看起来像这样的东西，一部电话
to be in paper form, which looks a little something like this, a phone
书。
book.
在一本老学校电话簿中确实是完全一样的主意。
And inside of an old school phone book really is that exact same idea.
它更大。
It's much larger.
它的印刷更多。
It's much more much more printed.
但这是同一回事。
But it's the same thing.
典型的电话簿中有一堆名字和电话号码，
There's a whole bunch of names and numbers in a typical phone book,
就像你自己的Android手机或iOS一样，按字母顺序排序
sorted alphabetically just like your own Android phone or iOS
手机也可以。
phone might be as well.
因此，假设我们要解决一个问题。
So suppose we want to solve a problem.
这个问题的输入不仅是电话簿，还有
And the input to that problem is not only this phone book, but also
查找号码的人的名字。
the name of someone to look up the number for.
因此，例如我自己的名字。
So my own name, for instance.
如果我想查找我的电话号码，或者你愿意，可以打开这本书
If I want to look up my phone number, or you do, you might open up this book
然后开始寻找戴维（David），
and start looking for David, for instance,
如果我们假设它是按名字排序的。
if we assume that it's sorted by first name.
我在第一页上没有看到David，所以我继续第二页。
I don't see David on the first page, so I move on to the second.
我在那儿看不到自己，所以我继续前进到第三位。
I don't see myself there, so I move on to the third.
我在那儿看不到自己，所以我继续前进到第四名。
I don't see myself there so I move on to the fourth.
依此类推，一次一页，寻找我的名字，然后，
And so forth, one page at a time, looking for my name and, in turn,
我的号码。
my number.
好吧，如果正确性很重要-让我先问这个问题。
Well, if correctness is important-- let me ask that question first.
是这种算法，一步一步地翻页，
Is this algorithm, turning the pages, step by step,
寻找大卫正确吗？
looking for David correct?
你怎么认为？
What do you think?
在Zoom中，你应该在参与者下方看到一些图标
Within Zoom, you should see some icons under the participants
标有“是”和“否”的窗口。
window labeled yes and no.
如果你想继续进行虚拟投票，是或否，
If you'd like to go ahead and vote virtually, yes or no,
这个算法正确吗？
is this algorithm correct?
一次一页，寻找自己。
One page at a time, looking for myself.
没关系，这是黄页的事实，
Never mind the fact that this is yellow pages,
所以我不会在电话簿中的任何地方，
and so I'm not going to be anywhere in the phone book,
但实际上，我们将假定它也包含人类。
but indeed, we'll assume it contains humans as well.
好的。
All right.
所以看起来算法确实是正确的，
So it looks like the algorithm is indeed correct,
但是它非常缓慢。
but it's terribly, terribly slow.
没关系，因为我们的想法之一
And that's OK, because one of the ideas we're
在CS50中考虑，然后在计算机科学中考虑，
going to consider in CS50 and in turn, computer science,
不仅是算法的正确性，而且是效率。
is not only the correctness of an algorithm, but also the efficiency.
算法设计得如何？
How well designed is the algorithm?
这是对的。
This is correct.
这是令人难以置信的，令人难以置信的乏味和缓慢的。
It's just incredibly, incredibly tedious and slow.
但是我会发现自己。
But I will find myself.
但是，当然，我们可以做得更好。
But, of course, we can do better.
而不是一次只找自己一页，我为什么不做一页，
Instead of looking for myself one page at a time, why don't I do one page,
我来做两个，四个，六个，八个，十个
let me do two, four, six, eight, 10.
听起来更快，也更快。
It sounds faster and it is faster.
我正在翻遍电话簿以查找自己的速度快一倍。
I'm going twice as fast through the phone book looking for myself.
这个算法正确吗？
Is this algorithm correct?
这次让我去听众。
Let me go to someone in the audience this time.
这是一次一次在两个页面上搜索某人姓名的算法吗
Is this algorithm of searching for someone's name two pages at a time
正确的？
correct?
因为我声称这样更有效。
Because I claim it's more efficient.
我声称它的设计更好，因为我能以两倍快的速度解决问题。
I claim it's better designed because I'll solve the problem twice as fast.
阿内卡，你怎么看？
Aneka, what do you think?
听众：否，因为你可能会跳过页面上的名字。
AUDIENCE: No, because you might skip your name on a page.
DAVID J MALAN：是的，我可能会在页面上跳过我的名字。
DAVID J MALAN: Yeah, I might skip my name on a page.
让我问一个后续问题。
And let me ask a follow up question.
我可以解决这个问题吗？
Can I fix this?
我是否必须放弃整个算法
Do I have to throw out the whole algorithm
还是我们至少可以解决这个问题，你认为吗？
or can we at least fix this problem, do you think?
观众：我认为无论你翻到哪一页，都会有帮助，
AUDIENCE: I think whatever page you flip to, it would help to see,
例如，那里有什么名字，也许看看你的名字会不会
like, what name is there and maybe see if your name would
之前或之后
come before or after.
DAVID J MALAN：好的。
DAVID J MALAN: Nice.
所以这是正确的直觉。
So that's exactly the right intuition.
我认为我们不必完全放弃加速的想法
I don't think we have to completely sacrifice the idea of speeding up
这种算法的移动速度是以前的两倍。
this algorithm by moving twice as fast.
但是，正如你所提议的那样，如果我走得太远，也许我会进入E部分，
But as you propose, if I go too far-- maybe I get to the E section,
太迟了一个字母-
which is one letter too late--
我应该至少翻回一页。
I should at least double back one page.
因为我可能会倒霉，也许是大卫
Because I could get unlucky, and maybe David
有点夹在两页之间，这时
is kind of sandwiched in between two pages, at which point
我可能飞过去，走到电话簿的结尾，说，不，没有大卫，
I might fly by, get to the end of the phone book, say, no, there's no David,
而且我不幸的是有50％的概率。
and I just got unlucky with 50% probability.
但是，正如你所提议的，我至少可以恢复并有条件地进行
But as you propose, I can at least recover and sort of conditionally
问自己，等一下，也许我只是错过了，然后再回头。
ask myself, wait a minute, maybe I just missed it, and double back.
这样我可以整体上提高速度，
So I can get the overall speed improvement,
但是至少可以解决这种错误或错误。
but then at least fix that kind of mistake or bug.
错误，是我们在编程中的一个术语，一个错误
And bug, a term of our-- in programming, a bug
仅仅是程序中的一个错误，或者更多
is just a mistake in a program, or a mistake, more
通常，在算法中。
generally, in an algorithm.
但老实说，我们谁也不会这样做。
But honestly, none of us are going to do that.
当我们实际去搜索电话簿中的某人时，
When we actually go to search for someone in a phone book,
就像我们的手机一样，它们通常不会从顶部开始
just like our phones do, they typically don't start at the top
并转到底部。
and go to the bottom.
而且计算机可以更直观地完成你可能要做的事情。
And computers do exactly what you might do more intuitively.
他们大概会走到中间。
They'll probably go roughly to the middle.
如果你知道的话，也许他们会向左倾斜一点
Maybe they'll skew a little to the left, if you know
D朝向字母的开头。
D is toward the start of an alphabet.
但是，不，我很随意地向中间开放，我处于M部分。
But, no I open to the middle sort of sloppily, and I'm in the M section.
那么，当我进入M部分时，该怎么办？
So what do I know when I'm in the M section about this problem?
让我再请一个人。
Let me call on one more person.
我在M部分。
I'm in the M section.
作为解决此问题的输入，你现在将如何做一个人？
What would you do as a human now, taking this as input to solve this problem?
我当然知道电话簿中我的名字的位置？
What do I know about the location, of course, of my name in the phone book?
我可以在这里做出什么决定？
What decision can I make here?
我可以做出什么决定？
What decision can I make?
凯尔，你怎么看？
Kyle, what do you think?
听众：是的。
AUDIENCE: Yeah.
因此，从M开始，你肯定不会知道你的名字。
So from the M onwards, you know that your name won't be there for sure.
DAVID J MALAN：是的，所以我的名字不会出现在M部分。
DAVID J MALAN: Yeah, so my name is not going to be in the M section.
但是，由于电话簿的字母顺序，我至少知道，
But thanks to the alphabetization of the phone book, I at least know,
你知道吗？
you know what?
我可以解决这个问题
I can take a huge bite out of this problem
从隐喻和字面意义上将问题分解成两半，
and tear the problem in half, both metaphorically and also literally,
如果是电话簿。
in the case of a phone book.
我实际上可以解决一半的问题。
And I can literally throw half of the problem away.
因此，如果我从这本电话簿中的第一千页开始
And so if I started with something like 1,000 pages in this phone book
或手机中的1,000个联系人，只需转到中间，
or 1,000 contacts in my phone, just by going to the middle,
粗略地看一下左右，我可以决定，
roughly, and taking a look to the left and the right, I can decide,
正如你所注意到的，它不在我要查找的页面上。
as you note, well, it's not on the page I'm looking for.
但是我可以决定它在左边还是右边。
But I can decide it's to the left or to the right.
我知道D在M之前出现。所以现在我可以向左走。
I know D comes before M. And so now I can go to the left.
你知道这里有趣的是，我
And you know what's interesting here, is that I
可以使用完全相同的算法。
can use that exact same algorithm.
我没有任何不同的想法。
I don't have to think any differently.
我可以应用相同的逻辑，打开电话的这半部分，预定
I can apply the same logic, open to the middle of this half of the phone, book
现在我看到我在“ G”部分。
and now I see I'm in the G section.
所以我还是有点太过分了。
So I'm still a little too far.
但是，我可以将一半的问题解决掉，把它扔下来
But again, I can tear half the problem away, throw it down
现在我已经从1000页增加到500页再增加到250页。
and now I've gone from, like 1,000 pages to 500 pages to 250 pages.
如果再次执行此操作，我可能会发现自己，哦，我现在进入了C部分。
If I do this again, I might find myself, oh, I made it to the C section now.
我可以再把问题撕成两半，丢掉剩下的一半，
I can tear the problem in half again, throw the left half away,
现在只有125页。
and now I'm down to just 125 pages.
现在，仍然很多，但我的天哪。
Now, that's still a lot, but my god.
我已经从1,000升至500到250升至125。
I've gone from 1,000 to 500 to 250 to 125.
那比从1,000到999到998快得多，
That is way faster than going from 1,000 to 999 to 998,
甚至比从1,000到998到996到994还要快。
and it's even faster than going from 1,000 to 998 to 996 to 994.
这两种算法都将花费我更长的时间。
Both of those algorithms are going to take me much longer as well.
我们有Brian制作的这种可视化效果，非常棒，
We have this visualization made by Brian, wonderfully,
描绘了1,024页的电话簿，一次翻一页。
that depicts 1,024 page phone book with one page being flipped at a time.
现在我们降到了996，995。
And now we're down to 996, 995.
我的意思是，老实说，这还不是很有启发性的。
I mean, honestly, this isn't all that enlightening.
在电话簿中找到David或任何名字将需要永远
It's going to take forever to find David or any name in a phone book
当以这种算法开始时。
when starting at that kind of pace with that algorithm.
但是，如果我更聪明些怎么办
But what if, instead, I'm a little smarter
我会更直观些吗？
and I'm a little more intuitive?
我利用了你和我可能拥有的直觉
And I harness the intuition that probably you had and I
再次从1,024页开始，这次
start with 1,024 pages again, and this time
一次分而治之，将问题一分为二吗？
divide and conquer, half at a time, splitting the problem in half?
将电话簿撕成两半，我只剩下一页。
Tearing the phone book in half, I get down to just one page.
如果我们实际进行数学计算，如果你的页面起始于1000多个页面，
And if we actually do out the math, if you start at like 1,000-plus pages,
下来，我只花了10滴电话簿的眼泪就可以掉下来
it will only take me 10 total tears of that phone book in order to get down
我的电话号码是949-468-2750。
to my number, 949-468-2750.
因此，这只是说第三种算法不仅正确，而且
So that just is to say that the third algorithm is not only correct, just
因为第一个肯定是，第二个可能是该错误修复，
as the first one definitely was and the second one could be with that bug fix,
但它的设计也更好。
but it's also much better designed.
效率更高。
It's much more efficient.
因此，我们也可以在图形上看到这一点。
And so we can see this a little graphically as well.
让我继续前进，不提出任何数值分析或其他任何建议
Let me go ahead and propose not a numerical analysis or anything
像那样。
like that.
但是只是一些像这样的视觉效果。
But just something that's a little visual like this.
所以如果我有一个x轴代表
So if I have an x-axis here that represents
从横向上看问题的大小，电话簿中的页数，
horizontally the size of the problem, the number of pages in a phone book,
垂直于y轴表示解决问题所需的时间。
and vertically on the y-axis, the amount of time required to solve a problem.
如果我们只是将它们绘制成图表，这些算法的外观如何？
What co these algorithms look like, if we just kind of chart them?
好吧，第一个算法（这里用红色表示）只是一条直线。
Well, the first algorithm, depicted here in red, it's just a straight line.
这是一个1的斜率，因为这是一对一的
It's a slope of one because there is this one to one
页数和时间之间的关系
relationship between number of pages and the amount of time
我需要解决它。
it takes me to solve it.
对于该电话簿的每个新页面，也许年复一年，
For every new page of that phone book, maybe year after year,
如果电话簿增长，它将带我
if the phone book grows, it's going to take me
进一步寻找自己或其他任何人，
one more step to look for myself or anyone else,
可能在该电话簿中。
potentially, in that phone book.
除非我很幸运，而且他们早在电话簿中，但是还有一个
Unless I get lucky and they're early in the phone book, but one more
翻页意味着再翻一页。
page means one more page turn.
第二种算法实际上更好。
The second algorithm is actually better.
仍然是一条直线。
It's still a straight line.
因此，它仍然是线性关系。
So it's still a linear relationship.
但是，电话簿中的每两页又使我迈出了一步。
But for every two pages in the phone book it takes me one more step.
两页，一圈。
Two pages, one turn.
因此，它绝对比第一种算法好。
So it's strictly better than the first algorithm.
为什么？
Why?
好吧，如果我们考虑到这一点-如果问题的严重性是
Well, if we consider this-- if the size of the problem is,
例如，也许在这里。
maybe, here, for instance.
因此，如果我们假设出于讨论目的，也许
So if we assume, for the sake of discussion, maybe
电话簿中有许多用虚线表示的页面。
the phone book has this many pages depicted with this dotted line.
好了，第二个算法要花多少时间
Well, how much time is it going to take the second algorithm
在电话簿中找人？
to find someone in that phone book?
这将花费大量时间，对吗？
It's going to take this amount of time, right?
那两条线相交的地方。
Where those two lines intersect.
不过，如果你使用的是第一种算法，则一次浏览一页，
If you're using the first algorithm, though, going one page at a time,
实际上，这将花费很多时间，这实际上是原来的两倍。
it's actually going to take this much time, which is literally twice as much.
因此，它们都是正确的，假设我们根据需要加倍返回
So they're both correct, assuming we double back as needed
如果我走了一个名字太远了。
if I go too far past a name.
但是，两者在本质上是相同的。
But both of those are sort of fundamentally the same.
它们是相同的形状，老实说，它们都
They're the same shape, and, honestly, they both
说话和行动起来很慢。
felt slow to say and to act out.
第三种算法，如果我们将其绘制成图形，
The third algorithm, if we were to graph it,
有根本不同的关系
has a fundamentally different relationship
在问题的大小和解决问题所需的时间之间。
between the size of the problem and the time required to solve the problem.
这条线应该向上，向上，向上，向上
The line goes up, up, up, up, as it should,
因为存在的页面越多，解决该问题所需的时间就越多，
because the more pages there are, the more time it's going to take to solve,
但请注意它上升的速度要慢得多。
but notice how much more slowly it goes up.
随着问题的严重，这件事几乎没有开始增加
This thing barely starts to rise as the size of the problem
变得越来越大。
gets bigger and bigger and bigger.
凭直觉为什么会这样呢？
And why is that, intuitively?
好吧，这里的功能强大的是，假设明年有电话簿，
Well, here, what's powerful is, suppose that phone book, next year,
无论出于何种原因，其大小都会增加一倍。
for whatever reason, doubled in size.
也许剑桥和马萨诸塞州的奥尔斯顿合并为一个
Maybe Cambridge and Allston, Massachusetts merged together into one
大型电话簿，所以现在有2,000多个页面。
big phone book, so there's 2,000-some-odd pages now instead.
明年还需要多少步骤
How many more steps would it take next year
在该电话簿中搜索某人？
to search for someone in that phone book?
一。
One.
更进一步。
One more step.
因此，如果你沿着这条绿线向此处看，
And so if you look way out here along this green line,
将电话簿的大小加倍
doubling the size of the phone book, the line
本身只会上升一点点，因为没什么大不了的。
itself is only going to rise ever so slightly because no big deal.
使用第三种算法，你可以从问题中解脱出来。
With that third algorithm you're taking much bigger bites out of the problem.
因此，这也说明了什么计算机科学和编程
And so this, too, speaks to what computer science and what programming
最终喜欢。
are ultimately like.
利用你进入课堂的想法
Harnessing ideas that you come into the class with
并可能会在你的日常生活中使用，
and that you might use in your everyday life,
但你不必思考如何表达问题
but you don't necessarily think about how you might represent problems
使用这些算法，以及如何将其转换为计算机语言。
using those algorithms and how you might translate them to computer speak.
实际上，我们将开始考虑算法的一种方式
And indeed, one way we'll start to think about algorithms
不仅是它们的正确性，还在于它们的设计水平。
is not only their correctness, but how well designed they are.
因此，例如在这里，我故意
And so for instance here, I've deliberately
将这三行标记为n，n标记为2，n标记对数为2。
labeled these three lines n, n over 2, and log base 2 over n.
这只是意味着如果我们将n用作数字-那么计算机科学家倾向于
That just means that if we use n as number-- so computer scientists tend
使用n作为变量，就像数学家可能会说x或y或z，
to use n as a variable, much like a mathematician might say x or y or z,
n为数字。
n for number.
所以第一条红线是运行时间，
And so the first red line is the running time,
解决问题可能要采取的步骤数
the number of steps it might take to solve a problem
在最坏的情况下，可能是n。
might be, in the worst case, n.
如果电话簿中有n页，也许我正在寻找某人的方式
If there's n pages in the phone book, maybe I'm looking for someone way
在电话簿的末尾
at the end of the phone book and it's going
带我全部n步找到它们。
to take me all n steps to find them.
第二种算法将采取一半的步骤。
The second algorithm is going to take half as many steps.
所以我们将其表示为n除以2，因为如果
So we express that as n divided by 2, because if we're
一次做两页，我们将到达电话簿的结尾-
doing two pages at a time we'll get to the end of the phone book--
例如，如果我们正在寻找名字以Z开头的人，
if we're looking for someone whose name starts with Z, for instance--
快一倍。
twice as fast.
但是第三种算法，如果你对数学有些生疏，
But the third algorithm, if you're a little rusty on the mathematics,
以2为底的对数表示。
is represented as a logarithm with a base of 2.
这只是表示该图，绿线
And this just means that this graph, the green line
描述每次通过需要多少时间来解决问题，
describes how much time it takes to solve a problem when on each pass,
在每一步中，你都将问题（在这种情况下）除以一半。
on each step, you are dividing the problem, in this case, by half.
其他两种算法可以解决这一问题。
The other two algorithms are taking one or two bites out of the problem.
第三种算法一次处理了整个问题的一半。
The third algorithm was taking half of the whole problem at a time.
这就是使它变得更加强大的原因。
And that's what made it all the more powerful.
所以说到现在的编程，我们需要
So when it comes to programming now, we need
将这些称为算法的东西翻译成代码。
to translate these things called algorithms to code.
或者，在这种情况下，我们称其为伪代码。
Or, in this case, let's call it pseudocode.
稍后，我们将专注于一种实际的编程语言，
And in just a bit, we'll focus on an actual programming language,
尽管是图形的。
albeit a graphical one.
但是现在，我们只考虑一些构造或排序
But for now let's just consider some of the constructs or sort
基本的想法将很有用
of fundamental ideas that are going to be useful to leverage
在这堂课上
here on out in this class.
因此，让我提出我实际上只是口头上所做的事情
So let me propose that what I really just did verbally
可以翻译成伪代码，就像实现的算法一样
can be translated into pseudocode, which is like an algorithm implemented
用英语，或你所说的口语或书面语言。
in English, or whatever your spoken or written language is.
但关键是它必须正确，
But the key is that it's got to be correct,
理想情况下最好是准确无误。
and ideally it had better be precise so that there's no ambiguity.
第一步确实是我所做的。
Step one was, indeed, what I did.
拿起电话簿。
Pick up phone book.
第二步，打开电话簿的中间。
Step two, open to middle of phone book.
第三步，看页面。
Step three, look at page.
确实，我做到了。
And indeed I did that.
现在事情变得有趣了。
And now things got interesting.
第四步，如果有人-
Step four, if person--
在我的情况下，David –在页面上，我想做什么？
David, in my case-- is on the page, what do I want to do?
好吧，我可能应该打电话给那个人。
Well, I should probably call that person.
问题已经解决了。
The problem is solved.
我已经得到了我的输出，那个人的号码。
I've gotten my output, the person's number.
但是还有另一种可能性，如果此人不在页面上
But there's another possibility, not if the person's on the page
但是，如果此人早于本书，
but, rather if the person is earlier in the book--
那就是刚才发生的事情。
and that is what happened a moment ago.
如果我最后选择了M，但我正在寻找David，那就在左边，
If I ended up on M, but I'm looking for David, that's to the left,
那我该怎么办？
I should then do what?
打开到书的左半部分的中间。
Open to the middle of the left half of the book.
这确实是我所做的。
And that's indeed what I did.
而且我无意间把问题解决了一半。
And I sort of gratuitously tore the problem in half.
但是从算法上讲，我只是看了下本书的左半部分。
But algorithmically, I just looked at the left half of the book next.
我下一步该怎么办？
What do I do next?
好吧，真的，这就是我要说的重点
Well, really, that's the point at which I
提出该算法现在一次又一次地可重复，
proposed that the algorithm is now just repeatable, again and again,
所以我们要说回到第三行。
and so we'll say go back to line three.
为什么？
Why?
好吧，从第三行开始，我有一个算法
Well, starting at line three, I have an algorithm
查找电话簿中的某人。
for looking up someone in a phone book.
碰巧的是，现在的电话簿只有原来的一半。
It just so happens the phone book now is half as large.
但是还有另一种情况。
But there's another case.
如果此人后来在书中怎么办？
What if the person is later in the book?
我不是在寻找以D开头的David，
I wasn't searching for David, which starts with D,
但是别人的名字都在字母表的末尾。
but someone else's name that's toward the end of the alphabet.
好吧，那么如果那个人在书的后面，那么同样的想法。
Well, then if that person is later in the book, same idea.
打开到书的右半部分的中间，
Open to the middle of the right half of the book,
然后再次返回到第三步。
and then again, go back to step three.
但最后，还有第四种可能性。
But lastly, there's a fourth possibility.
还有第四种可能性。
There's a fourth possibility.
该人在电话簿中，还是在左侧
Either the person's in the phone book, or they're to the left
或者它们在右边，或者坦率地说，它们根本不在那儿。
or they're to the right, or, frankly, they are just not there at all.
最后一点，尽管有些微妙，却非常重要。
And this last point, though somewhat subtle, is so important.
在Mac，PC上，我们所有人都有可能发生。
Odds are all of us on our Macs, PCs.
甚至手机，都曾经历过如此令人沮丧的经历
Maybe even phones, have had that very frustrating experience where
你的计算机挂起，却出现了愚蠢的旋转沙滩球或沙漏，
your computer hangs, you get the stupid spinning beachball or hourglass,
东西冻结或只是重新启动，你知道，出了点问题
the thing freezes or just reboots, you know, something goes wrong
这有点莫名其妙。
and it's sort of inexplicable.
你可能会认为这是你的错，但实际上是
And you might think it's your fault, but really it's
通常是程序员的过错，谁编写了你所需要的软件
usually the programmer's fault who wrote the software that you're
在你的计算机或设备上使用。
using on your computer or your device.
为什么？
Why?
不管出于何种原因，那个程序员经常
Very often, that programmer, for whatever reason,
没想到可能的情况。
did not anticipate a possible scenario.
在这种情况下，有四种情况，但是你
In this case, there's four scenarios, but you
可以想像有点忘记了事实，哦，也许大卫的
could imagine kind of forgetting the fact that, oh, well maybe David's
甚至在这本电话簿中也没有。
not even in this phone book.
但是你最好处理这种情况。
But you'd better handle that scenario.
当你的计算机死机或挂起时
And when you have a computer that freezes or hangs
或重新启动或出现问题，
or reboots or just something goes awry, that
通常只是因为人类没有
is quite often quite simply because a human did not
某些可能情况的代码。
code for some possible scenario.
那么我们的基本结构是什么
So what are the fundamental constructs we've
在这里看到我们将继续在课堂上看到吗？
seen here that we're going to continue seeing in class?
好吧，现在以黄色突出显示的实际上是一些动词或动作
Well, highlighted in yellow now are really some verbs or actions
我们用那本电话簿练习过的。
that we exercised with that phone book.
通常，这些在称为函数的编程中。
These are, in general, in programming called functions.
功能是动作或动词。
A function is an action or a verb.
这是使计算机执行某项操作的声明。
It's a statement that gets the computer to do something.
接下来要突出显示的是我们称为条件或分支的内容。
Next highlighted here are what we'll call conditions or branches.
这些是道路上众所周知的分叉。
These are sort of the proverbial forks in the road.
你既可以执行此操作，也可以执行此操作，也可以执行此操作。
You could either do this or this or maybe this other thing.
你可以做出一个决定，也可以做出两个，三个或四个决定，
And you can have one decision to make or two or three or four,
但是，从逻辑上讲，许多条件都是有意义的。
however many conditions make sense logically.
我们称这些条件。
We'll call those conditions.
但是，你如何决定走哪条路呢？
But how do you decide which fork in the road to take?
是否要执行此操作，该操作或其他操作？
Whether to do this or that or this other thing?
为此，我们需要一种称为布尔表达式的东西。
For that we need something called Boolean expressions.
一个布尔表达式，这只是一个问题
A Boolean expression it's just a question
其答案是“是”或“否”，或者是或否，或者坦率地说是“ 1”或“ 0”。
whose answer is yes or no, or true or false, or, frankly, one or zero.
所有这些对于我们的目的而言都是等效的。
All of those would be equivalent for our purposes.
所以页面上的人。
So person on page.
这是一个是或否的问题。
That's a yes or no question.
书中较早的人？
Person earlier in book?
这也是一个问题。
That too is a question.
书中后面的人也是第三个问题。
Person later in book is a third question as well.
因此，如果你可以想像是-否的答案，是非题，一个零答案，
So if you can imagine a yes-no answer, a true-false answer, a one-zero answer,
这就是给我们提供这些被称为布尔表达式的东西的原因。
that is what gives us these things called Boolean expressions.
最后，这些是黄色的东西。
And then lastly, in yellow here are these things.
回到第三行。
Go back to line three.
这将引发我们称为循环或循环的事情，
This will induce what we'll call a loop or a cycle,
这仅仅是程序的构造或算法的原理，
which is just a programming construct or principle of an algorithm that
让你一次又一次地做某事，所以你
gets you to do something again and again so you
不必编写100行算法。
don't have to write 100-line algorithm.
你可以编写一个13行算法，然后一次又一次地重用其中的一部分。
You can write a 13-line algorithm and reuse parts of it again and again.
因此，我们现在开始，我们将从外观上开始CS50
And so we'll begin now, and we'll begin CS50 with a look
使用一种实际的编程语言，你可能最近使用过一种
at an actual programming language, one that you might have used recently
还是年纪较小的孩子（称为Scratch），它是一种图形化编程
or as younger kids, known as Scratch, which is a graphical programming
虽然你们中的一些人可能很熟悉的语言，
language which, while it might be very familiar to some of you,
它实际上代表了许多编程基础知识
it actually represents a lot of these programming fundamentals
我们将在一周内将其用作过渡的基础
that we'll use as this ground for transitioning in just one week
到更传统，更古老的学校语言
to a more traditional more old school language,
称为C，完全基于文本和键盘。
known as C, which is entirely text and keyboard-based.
但是我们会在CS50中看到的所有语言中都可以看到，
But we'll see in all of the languages we look at in CS50,
这些东西称为函数和条件，布尔表达式
these things called functions and conditions, Boolean expressions
和循环，今天，在片刻中，我们将
and loops, and today, in just a moment, we'll
还可以看到我们描述为变量的其他一些功能，与x，y，
also see some other features that we describe as variables, not unlike x, y,
和z在数学，线程上，这似乎允许计算机执行操作，
and z in math, threads, which allow a computer to do, it would seem,
同时具有多个功能，事件和其他功能。
multiple things at once, events, and yet other features as well.
因此，从这里开始，我们从伪代码过渡到实际代码。
And so from here, we transition from pseudocode to actual code.
而你在屏幕上看到的是一个示例
And what you see on the screen here is an example
一种称为C的语言，我们将在其中花费大量时间
of a language called C, where we'll spend a good amount of time
本学期。
this semester.
这是较老的学校基于文本，基于键盘的语言
This is the older school text-based, keyboard-based language
我之前提到的。
to which I referred earlier.
但是这种语言有点神秘。
But this language is a bit cryptic.
当然，乍一看，你可能会想知道为什么其中存在井号，
And certainly at first glance, you might wonder why is the hash symbol there,
尖括号，括号，花括号，分号，
the angled brackets, the parentheses, the curly braces, the semicolon,
引号，我的意思是，我的天哪，屏幕上的内容有太多语法
the quotes, I mean, my god, there is so much syntax to what is on the screen
现在。
now.
你可能会猜到该程序的作用。
And you can probably guess what this program does.
让我快点到观众面前。
Let me just go quickly to the audience.
这个程序可能会做什么，即使你从未尝试过，
What, anyone, does this program probably do, even if you've never
编程过电脑吗？
programmed a computer before?
听众：它只是打印出你好，逗号，世界。
AUDIENCE: It just prints out hello, comma, world.
大卫·J·马兰（David J MALAN）：好的。
DAVID J MALAN: Exactly.
它只是打印你好，世界。
It just prints hello, world.
我的上帝，就像，看看所有的语法和所有的击键
And my god, like, look at all of the syntax and all of the keystrokes
我们只需要键入命令计算机即可。
we had to type just to command the computer to do that.
相比之下，今天是Scratch。
And so by contrast today is Scratch.
今天，我们将允许我们自己研究更多
We'll allow ourselves for just today to look at something much more
友好的，更加图形化的，这将使我们能够探索这些想法
friendly, much more graphical, that will allow us to explore these very ideas
并为更复杂，更传统的舞台打下基础
and set the stage for more sophisticated, more traditional
下周及以后的语言，但在上下文中
languages next week and beyond, but in the context
我们不必担心括号，分号，花括号，
where we don't have to worry about parentheses, semicolons, curly braces,
以及这些键在键盘上的位置。
and where even these keys are on the keyboard.
因此，请允许我向你介绍Scratch，
So allow me to introduce you, then, to Scratch,
由我们的一些朋友开发的
developed by some of our friends down the road
在麻省理工学院媒体实验室的剑桥。
here in Cambridge at MIT's Media Lab.
如果你想在scratch.mit.edu上玩，可以在这里在家玩。
You can play along at home here on out if you would like at scratch.mit.edu.
它是基于Web的，但也有一个脱机版本
It's web-based, but there's also an offline version
如果你往往没有最好的互联网。
if you tend not to have the best of internet.
但是用户界面通常看起来像这样。
But the user interface would typically look like this.
快速浏览。
And a quick tour.
因此，当你创建时，在草稿.mit.edu上
So here on scratch.mit.edu, when you go to create
通过界面上的按钮创建一个项目，你将首先看到Scratch，
a project via the button on the interface, you'll see first Scratch,
节目的同名人物，这只猫
the namesake of the program, this cat who
生活在这个可以移动的矩形小世界中，
lives in this little rectangular world in which you can move up,
向下，向左或向右。
down, left, or right.
但是猫可以被转换成任意数量的其他字符，
But the cat can be transformed into any number of other characters,
或我们称之为精灵的视觉表示。
or what we'll call sprites, visual representations thereof.
现在，这里的左侧是Scratch附带的所有构建块。
On the left here, now, are all of the building blocks that come with Scratch.
所有可用的编程结构
All of the programming constructs available to you
以拼图的形式。
in the form of puzzle pieces.
你会注意到，它们是根据
And you'll notice that they're categorized according
颜色和描述，还有一大堆拼图
to color and description and there's a whole bunch of puzzle pieces
而不是说他们做什么。
that rather say what they do.
今天的目标是不要陷入所有这些难题的杂草中
And today the goal is not to go into the weeds of all of these various puzzle
碎片，但强调一些可能的基本概念。
pieces, but to highlight some of the fundamental ideas that are possible.
我们将在此处通过屏幕中间探索这些想法。
And we'll explore those ideas via the middle of the screen here.
稍后，我们将能够开始拖放
We'll be able, in just a moment, to start dragging and dropping
这些拼图碎片放到更大的屏幕上
these puzzle pieces onto this larger screen
并将它们互锁在一起，如果这样做合乎逻辑。
and interlock them together, if it makes logical sense to do so.
最后，对于最复杂的程序，
Finally, for the most sophisticated programs,
我们实际上可以创建更多的角色或精灵
we can actually create yet more characters or sprites
并且实际上在屏幕上也有很多互动。
and actually have a lot of interactions on the screen as well.
但是，让我们继续前进，很快地举一个例子。
But let's go ahead and dive in with just an example quite quickly.
我要在屏幕上继续前进，确实要转到scratch.mit.edu。
I'm going to go ahead on my screen and go, indeed, to scratch.mit.edu.
也欢迎你在家中一起玩。
And you're welcome to play along at home as well.
我将单击“创建”以完全进入该界面。
And I'm going to click Create in order to get into exactly that interface.
除非你愿意，否则无需一开始就建立帐户。
You do not need to make an account from the get go unless you would like.
让我继续并开始创建程序。
And let me go ahead and start creating a program.
曾经是绝杀而编写的第一个程序，
The very first program that was once written, by lore,
简直就是Iris提出的“ Hello World”计划，
was quite simply what Iris proposed as "Hello World," a program that
在屏幕上打个招呼，世界。
prints on the screen hello, world.
好吧，我们该怎么做？
Well, how can we do that?
好吧，我可能很快就能做到
Well, I can probably do this quite quickly
因为我之前使用过界面，但是目标
because I've used the interface before, but the goal
如果你以前从未使用过此功能，
for you at hand if you've never used this before,
带着课程的第一个问题集或编程作业，真的
with the course's first problem set or programming assignment, really
只是让你的手变脏并探索和戳戳。
is just to get your hands dirty and explore and poke around.
很有可能，你正在寻找的想法最终会弹出。
And odds are, the ideas you are looking for, you'll find eventually pop out.
我要尝试的第一个是这里。
And the first one I'm going to try out is this one here.
这个拼图块是黄色或橙色的一点。
This puzzle piece that's a little yellow or orange in color.
它在“事件”类别中，单击绿色标记时将调用它。
It's in the Events category, and it's called when green flag clicked.
这很有趣，因为如果我在这里进入Scratch的舞台，
This is of interest, because if I go to Scratch's stage over here,
你会在左上角看到一个绿色标志，表示已通过，
you'll see at top left there's a green flag that's going to signify go,
还有一个红色的停止标志，表示停止。
and a red stop sign that's going to signify stop.
因此，如果我希望在单击该绿色标志时发生某些事情，
So if I want something to happen when I click that green flag,
我将从这个拼图开始。
I'm going to start with this puzzle piece here.
现在，我将进入“外观”类别。
Now I'm going to go over into the Looks category.
在“外观”类别中，有一大堆街区。
And in the Looks category, there's a whole bunch of blocks.
但是我们将在这里保持简单。
But we're going to keep it simple here.
我将继续讲Iris所说的规范，你好，逗号，
I'm going to go ahead and just say the canonical, as Iris noted, hello, comma,
世界。
world.
我将缩小。
I'll zoom back out.
我将移至此处的Scratch，然后单击绿色标志。
I'll move over to Scratch here, and I'm going to click now the green flag.
瞧，你好，世界。
And voila, hello, world.
这就是我的-也许很快，你的第一个程序，
So that is my-- and perhaps, soon, your-- very first program,
以这种语言使用Scratch。
using in this language Scratch.
但是，这当然不是很有趣。
But, of course, this isn't terribly interesting.
可能是第一次令人满足。
Might be gratifying for the very first time.
但这不是你想一次又一次地玩的东西。
But it's not something you'd want to play again and again.
但是我们可以使这件事更具互动性
But we can make this thing much more interactive
我们可以开始对这些构建基块进行分层
and we can start to layer these building blocks
并有一种类似于搜索电话簿的算法，
and have an algorithm more like searching that phone book,
有多个步骤。
that has multiple steps.
因此，让我继续并停止该程序。
So let me go ahead and stop that program.
让我来探索一下。
And let me explore a little bit instead.
这次，让我进入“感测”这个蓝色类别。
Let me go under Sensing this time, this blue category.
而且你将在这里看到此街区。
And you'll see this block here.
问你叫什么名字，然后等待。
Ask what's your name, and wait.
但是请注意，你的名字叫这个白色的椭圆形，
But notice that what's your name is in this white oval,
这意味着如果我想要，我可以更改问题所在，
and that implies that I can change what the question is if I want,
但我现在对这个问题还可以。
but I'm fine with that question for now.
让我继续，首先摆脱这些障碍，
And let me go ahead and first get rid of these blocks,
并在单击绿旗时给自己，这一次是在“传感”下
and give myself when green flag clicked, and this time start under Sensing
询问你叫什么名字，然后等待。
with ask what's your name and wait.
但是请注意，这是一个特殊的块。
But notice that this is kind of a special block.
它带有第二个块，即所谓的变量。
It comes with a second block, a so-called variable.
事实证明，这道谜题字面意思是
It turns out that this ask puzzle piece is literally
会问玩这个游戏的人一个问题，
going to ask the human who's playing this game a question,
并将该问题的答案存储在一个变量中，如图所示
and it's going to store the answer to that question in a variable, depicted
这里称为这个蓝色的椭圆形，称为答案。
here as this blue oval, called answer.
就像数学中一样，x，ay或z也是如此。
Just like in math, an x, a y, or a z.
那我该怎么办。
So what could I do with that.
好吧，让我再次进入外观。
Well, let me again go to Looks.
让我去打个招呼，但是这次，你知道吗？
Let me go to say hello, but this time, you know what?
让我继续打个招呼，逗号，然后-好吧，
Let me go ahead and say hello, comma, and then-- all right,
让我再说一遍。
let me give myself a second say block.
但我不想再打个招呼。
But I don't want to say hello again.
所以我要删除它。
So I'm going to delete that.
但是，我将回到“感测”，然后拖放答案。
But I'm going to go back to Sensing and I'm going to drag and drop answer.
现在看起来太大了，但是请注意，如果我接近它，
Now it looks a little too big, but notice if I get close to it,
有点磁性地想要连接。
it sort of magnetically wants to connect.
确实，Scratch会为我填补难题。
And indeed, Scratch will grow to fill the puzzle piece for me.
现在看来，我有一个用Scratch编写的程序，
So now I have a program, it would seem, a program written in Scratch,
一块用Scratch编写的软件，当绿色标志是
a piece of software written in Scratch that's going to, when the green flag is
单击，询问你的名字，然后等待-这就是我们的功能-
clicked, ask what's your name, and wait-- that's our function--
问好 -
say hello--
那是另一个功能-然后
that's another function-- and then it's going
无论人类输入什么，都可以说出答案。
to say answer, whatever the human typed in.
好吧，让我在这里转到Scratch的世界，然后单击绿色标志。
Well, let me go over to Scratch's world here and click the green flag.
注意猫在问我你叫什么名字。
Notice the cat is asking me what's your name.
我输入David并输入。
I type in David and enter.
嗯
Huh.
我只见大卫。
I only see David.
好吧，也许我做错了。
Well, maybe I did something wrong.
让我再做一次。
Let me do it again.
绿旗大卫（David）进入。
Green flag, D-A-V-I-D, enter.
唔。
Hmm.
这是怎么回事？
What's going on?
这似乎是一个错误，因为我很确定自己具有三个功能，
This seems to be a bug, because I'm pretty sure I have three functions,
问，说和说。
ask, say, and say.
但是我觉得我错过了第二条指令。
But I feel like I'm missing the second instruction.
对我犯了什么错误有任何想法吗？
Any thoughts on what bug I have made?
有什么解释呢？
What might explain this?
娜塔莉，是吗？
Natalie, is it?
听众：所以你用相同的功能替换了输出。
AUDIENCE: So you replaced the output with the same function.
大卫·J·马兰（David J MALAN）：是的。
DAVID J MALAN: Yeah.
我用相同的功能替换了输出。
I replaced the output with the same function.
老实说，即使我们使用的是一个非常简单的程序，Scratch，
And honestly, even though we're using a fairly simple program, Scratch,
我的Mac实际上非常快。
my Mac is actually pretty fast.
而且你的PC或Mac或手机都非常快。
And your PC or your Mac or your phone is pretty fast.
而且正如娜塔莉（Natalie）所说，即使Scratch在打招呼和回答，
And even though Scratch is saying hello and saying answer, as Natalie notes,
答案有点让人难以置信，因为我没有停下来。
the answer is sort of overwhelming to say, because I didn't so much as pause.
所以我可以进去找一个街区
So I could go in and find a block-- there's
一个等待块，可以让我插入一个任意的暂停。
a wait block that could allow me to insert an arbitrary pause.
但是我真的希望这是一口气。
But I really want this to be one breath.
我希望马上打个招呼，逗号，大卫。
I want it to be hello, comma, David, all at once.
那我该怎么办呢？
So how can I do that?
好吧，让我进入“操作”下。
Well, let me go under Operations.
事实证明，这里有一堆与数学相关的东西，
And it turns out there's a whole bunch of math-related things here,
而且这里还有一些与英语或语言相关的东西。
but also some English or language-related things down here.
加入苹果香蕉。
Join apple banana.
现在，这与苹果和香蕉无关。
Now this has nothing to do with apples and bananas.
这些只是占位符，但是这里有这个难题
Those are just placeholders, but there's this puzzle piece here
我可以拖放。
that I can drag and drop.
你知道吗？
And you know what?
让我继续执行此操作。
Let me go ahead and do this.
让我替换第一个输入要说的内容，然后让我加入问候逗号，然后
Let me replace the first input to say, and let me join hello comma, and then
不是香蕉，而是让我拖延答案-
not banana, but let me drag the answer--
并注意该位置会下降。
and notice that will drop in place.
让我把另一个方块扔掉。
Let me throw this other block away.
要删除内容，你只需将它们拖到左侧并放开即可。
To delete things, you can just drag them over to the left and let go.
现在请注意，我有一个程序正在询问你的名字
And now notice that I have a program that's asking what's your name
然后我要说说加入问候和回答的结果。
and then I'm going to say the result of joining hello and answer.
让我继续，并在停止旧版本后立即播放。
And let me go ahead and play this now, after stopping the old one.
你叫什么名字？
What's your name?
我输入David，输入，然后瞧。
I type in David, enter, and voila.
正如娜塔莉（Natalie）所说，现在它并没有绊倒自己，
As Natalie notes, now it's not tripping over itself,
破坏以前的存在。
clobbering what was previously there.
现在，我一口气得到了这一切。
Now I'm getting it all in one breath.
现在该程序变得更加有趣了，
Now the program is getting a little more interesting,
但是这种范式与以前没有什么不同。
but the paradigm is no different from before.
实际上，让我提出我们刚刚完成的所有工作
In fact, let me propose that everything we've just done
完全适合什么的整个心理模型
is fitting perfectly into this whole mental model of what
它意味着解决问题以及计算机科学本身是什么。
it means to solve problems and what computer science itself is.
因此，例如，如果这是要解决的问题
So for instance, if this is the problem to be solved
我有输入和输出是我的目标，还有两者之间的算法，
and I've got inputs and outputs are my goal and an algorithm in between,
让我们考虑一下Scratch如何适应这种心理模型。
let's consider how Scratch even fits into this mental model.
我刚才输入的第一个程序的输入
My input to the very first program that we wrote a moment ago
从字面上打招呼，它的椭圆形世界。
was literally hello, world in its own oval.
该算法在Scratch中被实现为一个称为say的函数。
The algorithm was implemented as a function in Scratch called say.
因此，有一个算法，分步说明，
So an algorithm, step by step instructions,
函数是计算机对算法的实现。
a function is the computer's implementation of an algorithm.
在这种情况下，称为say的功能。
In this case, a function called say.
当然，输出的是猫在打招呼，世界。
The output, of course, was the cat saying hello, world.
但是，纳塔莉（Natalie）发表讲话后，事情变得更加有趣了。
But things got more interesting just now after Natalie's remark, whereby when I
介绍一些类似的问题，问你叫什么名字，然后等待，
introduce something like ask what's your name and then wait,
注意这次在模型中发生了什么。
notice what happens this time in the model.
现在问题的输入是你的名字-
Now the input to the problem is what's your name--
那是默认情况下出现的字符串，我可以更改它，但是没有。
that's the string that comes by default, and I could change it but I didn't.
现在将其输入到ask块中。
That's being fed now into the ask block.
问块的生活目的是养猫
And the ask block's purpose in life is to get the cat
给我一个这样的答案
to give me an answer like this.
现在，这个答案很有趣，因为我现在可以加入它
Now, that answer is interesting because I can now join it
以单词hello作为前缀。
in with the word hello as a prefix.
因此，此块很有趣，因为注意，输入，
So this block is interesting because notice, the input,
“说”方块的白色椭圆形实际上还有另一个拼图块，然后
the white oval to the say block actually has another puzzle piece and then
在它上面还有两个拼图。
two more puzzle pieces on top of it.
这里很酷的是，在对函数进行编程时，
And what's cool here is that when programming functions,
你可以使一个功能的输出成为另一功能的输入。
you can have the outputs of one function become the input to another function.
因此，这里的流程非常简单。
And so the flow here is quite simply this.
现在我有两个输入到函数，两个都是你好，我写的，
Now I have two inputs to the function, both hello, which I wrote,
和答案，这是来自Ask块的。
and answer, which came from the ask block.
现在有问题的算法是我刚刚使用的联接函数。
The algorithm in question now is the join function, which I just used.
希望它的输出会打招呼，逗号，大卫。
And its output is hopefully going to be hello, comma, David.
但我不想在屏幕上看到一个白色的椭圆形，问好，逗号，大卫。
But I don't want to see a white oval on the screen saying hello, comma, David.
我要猫打招呼，逗号，大卫。
I want the cat to say hello, comma, David.
因此，让我继续，只专注于输出。
So let me go ahead and focus only on the output.
使它成为最终功能的输入，也就是块，
Make it become the input to a final function, which is that say block,
瞧，现在猫说了我想要的。
and voila, now the cat says what I want it to.
再说一遍，即使你开始筑巢，也要放置这些拼图
So again, even as you start to nest, that is, place these puzzle pieces
一个在另一个之上，我们要做的就是传递输入
one on top of the other, all we're doing is passing in inputs
并获得输出。
and getting outputs.
对这些输出进行处理，然后使它们成为输入，依此类推。
Doing something with those outputs and making them inputs, and so forth.
最终，这实际上就是编程意味着什么。
That really is the paradigm, ultimately, of what it means to program.
但是我们可以使猫做更多有趣的事情。
But we can make the cat do more interesting things.
只是为了从中获得一点乐趣，
And just to have a little bit of fun with this,
让我继续深入此底部图标
let me go ahead and dig in to this bottom icon
在屏幕的左下方。
at the bottom left of the screen.
Scratch具有这些所谓的扩展程序，你可以在其中真正地
Scratch has these so-called extensions, where you can really
使其做得更好。
make it do fancier things as well.
让我转到右上角的“文本到语音”。
And let me go to Text to Speech at the top right.
所以这是使用基于云的服务-
So this is using a cloud-based service--
这是一些基于互联网的服务-
that is some internet-based service--
这将发送我在互联网上输入的单词。
that's going to send the words that I type out on the internet.
互联网，那里的一些服务器，将以口头表达来回应
The internet, some server there, is going to respond with a verbalization
现在我刚刚输入的内容。
now of what it is I just typed.
因此，让我继续尝试。
So let me go ahead and try this.
让我摆脱紫色语音功能
Let me get rid of the purple say function
并替换为该语音块。
and replace it with this speak block.
让我继续并拖入拼图
And let me go ahead and drag in the join puzzle piece
在这里-请注意，它将不断增长，
here-- notice it's going to grow to fill,
而且我将不再使用它。
and I'm not going to use this one anymore.
这次我要点击“停止”，然后继续
This time I'm going to hit Stop and I'm going to go ahead
然后再次点击播放，然后输入我的名字。
and hit Play once more and type in my name.
和 -
And--
计算机：（女性机器人）你好，大卫。
COMPUTER: (FEMININE ROBOTIC) Hello, David.
DAVID J MALAN：好的，不是很自然的猫声音，
DAVID J MALAN: OK, not a very natural cat sound,
但请注意，我们可以设置不同的声音。
but notice we can set the voice differently.
因此请注意，我可以拖动此拼图。
So notice I can drag this puzzle piece.
你甚至可以将砖块挤压在其他砖块内。
And you can even squeeze blocks inside of others.
请注意，它可以随心所欲。
Notice that it can go wherever you want.
我将其放在此处的最高位置。
I'll put it at the very top here.
所以我可以把它放在几个不同的地方。
So I could put it in a couple of different places.
现在，默认声音是女低音。
Right now the default voice is alto.
吱吱声听起来合适。
Squeak sounds appropriate.
让我们尝试一下。
Let's try that.
键入我的名字，大卫。
Typing in my name, David.
计算机：（高音调）你好，大卫。
COMPUTER: (HIGH PITCHED) Hello, David.
DAVID J MALAN：好的。
DAVID J MALAN: All right.
还是不太像猫。
Still not very catlike.
具有讽刺意味的是，有一种小猫的声音，如果我改成小猫的话，
Ironically, there is a kitten voice, which if I change it to kitten,
我们现在将听到此消息。
we'll now hear this.
输入我的名字并输入。
Type in my name and enter.
计算机：（高音调）喵喵。
COMPUTER: (HIGH PITCHED) Meow meow.
DAVID J MALAN：好的，那时候我键入的内容并不重要。
DAVID J MALAN: OK, so it doesn't really matter at that point what I type in.
但是现在，这太神奇了。
But now this is amazing.
就像，我们已经从仅仅打个招呼，世界到打招呼，
Like, we've gone from just saying hello, world to hello,
大卫，这是动态变化的。
David, which is dynamically changing.
显然，如果你输入姓名，
If you were to type your name, obviously,
它会说你的名字。
it would say your name instead.
现在，由于有了云，也就是说，互联网上的服务器，
And now, thanks to the cloud, that is, servers on the internet,
我们会自动转换人类刚刚拥有的文本
we're converting automatically text that the human has just
提供到声音文件中-
provided into a sound file--
注释和持续时间，以及所有这些-
notes and durations and all of that--
变成我的计算机现在可以播放的内容。
into something my computer can now play.
好吧，让我们实际使这只猫听起来更像只猫。
Well, let's actually make this cat sound a little more like a cat.
让我继续前进，摆脱那些障碍
Let me go ahead and get rid of those blocks
在这里，让我现在从声音类别中讲一下自己，
here, and let me go and give myself now from the sound category,
这个怎么样？
how about this?
播放声音直到完成。
Play sound meow until done.
现在，这是一个简单的程序。
Now, this is a simple program.
单击绿色标志时，播放声音直到完成。
When the green flag is clicked, play sound meow until done.
开始了。
Here we go.
我要继续玩Play。
I'm going to go ahead and hit Play.
[喵]
[MEOW]
好吧，就是这样。
All right, that's it.
如果我想再次听到猫的叫声，我必须再做一次。
If I want to hear the cat meow again, I got to do it again.
[喵]
[MEOW]
太棒了。
OK, that's great.
只需单击一下，我就可以使自己好一阵子
I could kind of amuse myself for a while by just clicking--
[喵]
[MEOW]
-播放，但是-
--play, but--
[喵]
[MEOW]
-当然，我们可以做得更好。
--surely we can do better than this.
你可以想象-
You can imagine this--
[喵]
[MEOW]
-很快变得乏味。
--getting tedious quickly.
那么我怎样才能让猫一次又一次地这样做呢？
So how might I get the cat to do this again and again?
好吧，你知道吗？
Well, you know what?
让我继续前进，让我稍微抓住其中的一些。
Let me go ahead and let me just kind of grab a few of these.
喵，喵，喵，三遍。
Meow, meow, meow, three times.
因此，现在我不必再按两次按钮了。
So now that's two fewer times I have to hit the button.
[快速播放3次]
[MEOWING THREE TIMES RAPIDLY]
好的。
All right.
看起来好像不是最快乐的猫。
It doesn't seem like the happiest cat.
因此，让我实际去控制中心，让我再给他第二个休息时间。
So let me actually go to Control and let me give him a second break in between.
在这里等一会儿。
Wait one second in between here.
现在让我再来一次。
Now let me do it again.
[放映三遍]
[MEOWING THREE TIMES]
好吧，猫要快乐一些。
OK, slightly happier cat.
但这现在看起来有点混乱。
But this seems a little messy now.
这是对的。
This is correct.
叫三声。
It is meowing three times.
但是，让我去听众。
But let me go to the audience.
现在让我们考虑设计。
Let's now consider design.
回想一下，我们在电话簿的上下文中考虑了设计。
Recall that we considered design in the context of the phone book.
第三种算法设计得更好，因为它更快，
The third algorithm was better designed in that it was faster,
它效率更高，但是还有另一个要素
it was more efficient, but there's another element
设计，那就是如果可能的话，你不应该重复自己。
to design, which is that you shouldn't repeat yourself if possible.
所以你们那些以前编程的人
So those of you who have programmed before
可能知道这里的解决方案可能是什么。
might know what the solution here might be.
好吧，事实证明，回到第三行，我们称之为循环。
Well, it turns out that go back to line three, we call a loop.
事实证明，Scratch支持这些称为循环的事情。
Turns out Scratch supports these things called loops.
而且，实际上，这里有人盯着我。
And, in fact, there's one staring at me right here.
如果我向左放大，请注意在控制块下方，
If I zoom in on the left, notice that under the control blocks,
这些橙色方块有一个重复方块。
these orange blocks there's a repeat block.
即使默认情况下它为10，我敢打赌我们也可以更改它。
And even though it says 10 by default, I bet we can change that.
因此，让我将其拖到此处。
So let me drag that over here.
让我丢掉很多这种多余的东西，这些副本粘贴。
Let me throw away a lot of this redundancy, this copy paste.
让我将这些拼图碎片移动到重复块中，
Let me move these puzzle pieces inside of the repeat block,
而且它也会增长以适合他们。
and it, too, will grow to fit them.
没问题
Not a problem.
让我将重复次数更改为三个。
Let me change the repeat to three.
现在让我重新连接一切。
And now let me reconnect everything.
现在，该程序更加严格了。
And now the program is just tighter.
它使用更少的拼图块或更少的代码行，
It's using fewer puzzle pieces, or fewer lines of code,
如果你愿意的话，只需更少的步骤即可达到相同的结果。
fewer steps, if you will, to achieve the same result.
所以现在如果我单击绿色标记-
So now if I click the green flag--
[放映三遍]
[MEOWING THREE TIMES]
-它仍在工作。
--it's still working.
因此，你可以想象将其更改为所需的任何数字。
So you could imagine changing this to any number you want.
甚至有一个永远的障碍，我们可以永远做到，
There's even a forever block, where we could do it forever,
如果这只猫将永远这样做。
if the cat's going to do this in perpetuity.
但这是一个更好的程序。
But it's a better program now.
现在设计更好，因为如果我想更改时间量
Now it is better designed, because if I want to change the amount of time
猫在等我还是要换
the cat is waiting or if I want to change
猫叫的总次数，我
the total number of times the cat meows, I
可以在一处而不是一两个或三个地方更改这些详细信息，
can change those details in one place, not in one or two or three,
就像通过复制和粘贴相同的拼图一样。
as by copying and pasting those same puzzle pieces.
好吧，那永远的循环呢？
Well, what about that forever loop?
如果你确实想永远做某事怎么办？
What if you do want to do something forever?
我想怎么办？
What might I want to do?
好吧，让我们起床并动起来。
Well, let's get the cat up and moving.
现在让我进入运动类别。
Let me go under the motion category now.
让我指向鼠标指针。
Let me go to point towards mouse pointer.
因此，让我放大一下。
So let me zoom in on this.
每当猫指向鼠标指针时，
And every time the cat points toward the mouse pointer,
让他迈出一步。
let's have him take one step.
因此，我将采取一些步骤，
So I'm going to grab the move some number of steps,
我将把10改成1。
and I'm going to change the 10 to a one.
现在我要打Play。
And now I'm going to hit Play.
现在我们有了第一个程序，猫在哪里
And now we have our first program where the cat is
对我的Mac光标的响应。
kind of responding to my Mac's cursor.
我可以四处移动，有点傻瓜，
And I can move it around, and I can kind of get a little goofy,
但是从字面上带走了我。
but it's taking me literally.
它指向鼠标光标，然后向前移动了一步。
It's pointing at the mouse cursor and it's then moving one step.
现在，我可以使其移动更快。
Now, I can make it move faster.
让我停一秒。
Let me stop this for a second.
如果我一次不走一步，而是一次走两步怎么办？
What if I move not one step at a time, but two steps at a time?
而且我们会看到，猫现在移动得更快了。
And we'll see that now the cat is moving a little faster.
不太快。
Not quite super fast.
让我们一次执行20个步骤，看看会发生什么。
Let's do 20 steps at a time and see what happens.
这确实是动画的本质。
And this is really the essence of animation.
你调整的步数或更改数量越多
The more you adjust the number of steps or the number of changes happening
每秒或每单位时间的像素数，
to those pixels per second or per unit of time,
在屏幕上视觉上会发生更多的事情。
the more that's going to happen visually on the screen.
好吧，仅仅跟随我们还能做些什么？
Well, what more can we do from just following?
好吧，你知道吗？
Well, you know what?
如果我现在有能力让猫跟着我，
If I have the ability now to have the cat follow me,
让我一起尝试其他东西。
let me try something else altogether.
让我继续，打开另一个扩展。
Let me go ahead and open up another extension.
让我进入钢笔工具
Let me go into the Pen tool, which is going
现在让我在屏幕上用铅笔或钢笔绘图。
to allow me now to draw with, like, a pencil or pen on the screen.
我想让猫继续跟着我走，
And let me go ahead and still have the cat follow me, I think--
其实，你知道吗？
actually, you know what?
让我们改变这个。
Let's change this.
让他去我现在的位置。
Let's just have him go to where I am.
因此，还有另一个方块表示转到随机位置。
So there's another block that says go to random position.
我不要
I don't want that.
所以我将通过小三角菜单来更改它
So I'm going to change it by the little triangle menu
在这里，转到鼠标指针。
here, to go to the mouse pointer.
所以现在，永远，猫只会去到鼠标指针所在的位置。
So now, forever, the cat's just going to go to where the mouse pointer is.
它不会滑行或缓慢或快速地滑行。
It's not going to glide or do it slowly or quickly.
它只会移至光标所在的位置。
It's just going to go to wherever the cursor is.
现在，让我现在转到下面的这个新的Pen类别。
And let me go now to this new Pen category down below.
我该怎么办呢？
And how might I do this?
你知道我想要什么？
You know what I want?
我希望这只猫能为我画画。
I want this cat to be able to draw for me.
当我上下左右移动光标时，
When I move the cursor up, down, left, right, I
想要在屏幕上实际用墨水画些东西。
want to actually draw something with ink on the screen.
但是我只想在笔落下时画些东西。
But I only want to draw something when the pen is down.
请注意左侧，我刚刚介绍的两个拼图中的两个
Notice on the left that two of the two puzzle pieces I just introduced over
左边是笔向下和笔向上。
here at left are pen down and pen up.
但是这里缺少一些逻辑。
But there's a piece of missing logic here.
让我问听众，我们将如何改进该计划
Let me ask the audience how might we go about enhancing this program
这样猫不仅会跟随我的光标，而且还会在屏幕上画画？
so not only does the cat follow my cursor, but I also draw on the screen?
尼古拉斯，你会提出什么样的解决方案？
Nicholas, what kinds of solutions would you propose?
观众：所以你可以做一个if陈述-
AUDIENCE: So what you could do is take an if statement--
这样你就可以控制何时打开笔或何时向下笔，
so you can control when the pen is up or when the pen is down,
取决于你的某些情况。
depending on some condition that you have.
就像，我知道很多事情，都是通过单击鼠标来绘制的，
Like, I know a lot of things, you draw with the mouse click,
如果鼠标处于打开状态，则可以说笔处于关闭状态。
if the mouse is on, then you can say the pen is down.
而且，当没有单击鼠标时，笔就起来了。
And when the mouse click is not on, your pen is up.
然后，尽管它永远跟随着它
And then while it follows it forever it also
可以查看你的鼠标单击是打开还是关闭。
senses to see if your mouse click is on or off.
我真的不知道
I don't really know.
DAVID J MALAN：不，你确实知道。
DAVID J MALAN: No, you really do know.
那真是太完美了。
That was, like, perfect.
因为你本着永远拥有的原则
Because you took this principle of having the forever
不仅阻止了鼠标指针，而且你建议
block not only go to the mouse pointer, but you proposed
根据条件提出问题。
asking a question by a condition.
因此，让我实际上处于控制之下
So let me actually go under Control, where
我碰巧知道这个拼图是，并且注意到类似于我们的电话簿
I happen to know this puzzle piece is, and notice similar to our phone book
伪代码，我在这里说过，如果还有，如果还有，
pseudocode, where I said if else, if else, if else, well,
我认为，正如你所建议的，这里只有两个问题。
here there's only two questions, I think, as you're proposing.
鼠标按钮是向下还是向上？
Is the mouse button down or up?
因此，我认为我们可以通过其他方式摆脱困境。
So I think we can get away with just an if else.
因此，让我继续并将其拖到鼠标指针下方。
So let me go ahead and drag this below the go to mouse pointer.
然后注意中间的这种梯形形状
And then notice this little trapezoid-like shape in the middle
这里。
here.
让我在这里去传感。
Let me go to Sensing here.
请注意，如果我向下滚动，是的。
And notice if I scroll down-- yep, there it is.
在左边，注意到这个了吗？
On the left, notice this one?
鼠标按下，问号？
Mouse down, question mark?
这些是我们的布尔表达式。
These are our Boolean expressions.
让我将该布尔表达式拖动到类似的形状中。
Let me drag that Boolean expression into that similar shape.
它会不断增长以适应它。
It's going to grow to fit it.
然后我想怎么办？
And then what do I want to do?
如果鼠标按下，我想我想把笔放下。
If the mouse is down, I think I want to put the pen down.
否则，如果鼠标隐含地抬起，让我继续进行操作，然后将笔抬起
Else, if the mouse is implicitly up, let me go ahead and put the pen up
像这样。
like this.
好吧，让我继续全屏显示
Well, let me go ahead and full screen this, just
这样我们可以看到更好的效果。
so we can see a little better.
让我点击播放。
Let me hit Play.
现在，这只猫正按照我的承诺跟着我走。
And now the cat is following me, as promised.
但这现在是一只绘图猫。
But this is now a drawing cat.
如果我单击鼠标按钮，我会说类似的话，草书很差，
If I click the mouse button, I can say something like, very poorly in cursive,
你好。
Hello.
有点。
Sort of.
自从我做草书以来已经有很长时间了。
Been a long time since I've done cursive.
因此，我们现在让猫实际上在画些东西。
So we now have the cat actually drawing something.
老实说，这是只猫在画，这有点荒谬。
And honestly, it's a little ridiculous that it's a cat drawing.
但是你知道吗？
But you know what?
Scratch有这些服装。
Scratch has these costumes.
我们可以在这里左上角，即使Scratch带有两只猫
We could go at top left here, and even though Scratch comes with two cat
服饰，我们可以将其更改为笔或记号笔，或者实际上是任何东西
costumes, we could change it to be a pen or a marker or, really, anything
我们想要。
we want.
因为归根结底，这个精灵
Because at the end of the day, this sprite
实际上只是屏幕上的一个字符
is really just a character on the screen that
可以采用我们可能想要的任何形式。
can take any form that we might want.
好吧，我们如何才能进一步做到这一点？
Well, how can we take this further?
我喜欢这种条件和循环的介绍，
I like this introduction of conditions and loops,
但是我们可以在这里介绍其他一些原则。
but there's some other principles we can introduce here.
让我继续在这里开始一个新程序。
Let me go ahead and start a new program here altogether.
让我们看看我们是否无法开始计数
And let's see if we can't start counting up
并开始跟踪信息。
and start keeping track of information.
所以这次，让我们开始吧。
So for this time, let's do this.
单击绿色标志后，这次让我们进入变量
When the green flag is clicked, this time let's go under variables
让我们给自己一个新的变量。
and let's give ourselves a new variable.
从头开始，你可以创建拼图块，这是一个变量，
Scratch lets you create puzzle pieces, this one being a variable,
我将其称为计数器。
and I'm going to call this a counter.
只是一些要不断增加的东西。
Just something that's going to keep count from one on up.
现在，这给了我一些自定义的拼图
Now this has given me some custom puzzle pieces over here
称为计数器，然后是默认的我的变量，该变量已经存在。
called counter, and then the default my variable, which was there already.
我将继续执行此操作。
And I'm going to go ahead and do this.
我将计数器初始设置为1。
I'm going to set the counter initially equal to one.
然后我将永远做某事。
And then I'm going to do something forever.
让我抓住那些永远的障碍之一。
Let me grab one of those forever blocks.
我希望这只猫永远做下去。
And I want the cat now to do this forever.
我希望它只说当前的数量。
I want it to just say whatever the current count is.
所以我不想两秒钟打招呼。
So I don't want it to say hello for two seconds.
我想说一秒。
I want it to say something for one second, let's say.
因此，我将回到变量。
So I'm going to go back to variables.
我要抓住我创建的这个新的圆形计数器
And I'm going to grab this new circular shape, counter, that I created
并将其拖到那里。
and drag it right there.
因此，你可以从上到下逐字阅读。
So you can read this literally top to bottom.
所以数到一，然后等一会儿。
So counter to one, then forever say the counter for one second.
但是如果我们不希望猫一次又一次地说相同的数字，
But if we don't want the cat to say the same number again and again and again,
让我们继续前进，将计数器换一。
let's go ahead and change the counter by one.
这将隐式地将其添加到计数器中。
And that's implicitly going to add one to the counter.
现在，如果我继续点击播放，我们会看到一只猫
Now if I go ahead and hit Play, we see a cat
从一数到二到三，
that's counting from one to two to three,
理想情况下，它会一直计数到无穷大。
and it's going to count up, ideally, all the way to infinity.
现在不同了，我们有这个功能
The difference being now, we have this feature
实际使用一个变量，一个保持不变的变量
of actually using a variable, a variable that's keeping
跟踪一些信息。
track of some amount of information.
在这种情况下，数量会不断更新，
In this case, the number that's constantly being updated,
屏幕将一次又一次地重绘。
and the screen is being redrawn again and again.
好吧，现在让我继续，然后开始打开
Well, now let me go ahead and just start opening
我事先写的一些程序
a few programs that I wrote in advance, just
这样我们就可以浏览其中的一些。
so that we can get a tour of some of those.
我有一个名为Bounce的程序，它的工作原理如下。
I've got this program called Bounce that works a little something like this.
这也是编程的一部分。
And this, too, is part of programming.
不仅要编写自己的代码，还要阅读自己的代码。
Not only writing your own code, but reading your own code.
让我继续放大我已经创建的内容，
And let me go ahead and zoom in on this, which I've already created,
并考虑它的意思。
and consider what it says.
第一组，旋转样式，左，右。
First set, rotation style, left, right.
这只是一个修复，否则将是猫不小心遇到的错误
This is just a fix what would otherwise be a bug where the cat accidentally
最终倒挂。
ends up upside down.
但是，让我对此挥手。
But let me wave my hand at that.
这是有趣的部分。
This is the interesting part.
猫永远走了10步。
Forever have the cat moved 10 steps.
然后，如果它接触到边缘，则旋转180度。
And then if it's touching the edge, then turn around 180 degrees.
现在，我们可以重新介绍动画的概念。
So now we can reintroduce the idea of animation.
但这不是由我（人类）用光标驱动的。
But not that's driven by me, the human, with my cursor.
我现在可以制作游戏，互动艺术品或其他任何东西
I can now make a game, and interactive piece of art, or anything
现在这只猫是自我驱动的。
now where the cat is self-driven.
因为当我点击“立即播放”时，请注意
Because when I hit Play now, notice that it's
来回移动。
moving back and forth, back and forth.
如果它触碰到边缘和答案
And if it is touching the edge and the answer
这个布尔问题的答案实际上是“是”或“是”或“一个”
to that Boolean question is, actually, yes or true or one,
然后它将旋转180度。
then it's going to turn 180 degrees.
诚然，这看起来有点愚蠢。
But this looks kind of stupid, admittedly.
你知道，一只猫，是的，正在从屏幕上跳下来，
You know, one, the cat, yes, is bouncing off the screen,
这可能有点不现实。
which is maybe a little unrealistic.
但是他并没有真正走路。
But he's not really walking.
他在滑行。
He's gliding.
但这是关于动画的事情。
But this is the thing about animation.
就像我们在录像之前提到的那样，在一天结束时，
Just as we noted before that videos, at the end of the day,
实际上只是图像在屏幕上飞舞
are really just images flying across the screen--
你知道吗？
you know what?
我敢打赌，就像真实的视频中一样，我们可以创造自己的运动错觉，
I bet we can create our own illusion of movement, just like in a real video,
不仅穿着一种服装，一只猫的脚像这样。
by taking not just one costume, the cat with his feet like this.
如果我们给自己第二套服装，那几乎是一样的怎么办
What if we gave ourselves a second costume, where it's almost the same
但他的脚的位置略有不同？
but his feet are slightly differently positioned?
就像我们之前看过的纸质活页簿一样。
Just like the paper based flipbook that we looked at earlier.
你知道吗？
And you know what?
我敢打赌，如果我在这两种服装之间切换，
I bet if I toggle between these two costumes,
一次又一次地改变猫的状况，
changing the condition of the cat again and again,
我敢打赌，我们可以制造出实际运动的错觉。
I bet we can create the illusion of actual movement.
这就是我们在另一个弹跳示例中所拥有的。
And that's what we have here in this other bounce example.
在另一个弹跳示例中，我们现在正在移动猫
In this other bounce example, we have the cat now moving
不仅来回，而且注意这个紫色的拼图。
not only back and forth, but notice this purple puzzle piece.
从边缘弹起或考虑从边缘弹起后，
After it bounces off the edge, or considers bouncing off the edge,
它不断地改变其服装到下一个，到下一个，
it constantly changes its costume to the next one, to the next one,
到下一个，基本上是两者之间的交替
to the next one, essentially alternating between the two.
所以现在还不是很完美。
So now it's not quite perfect.
就像，我们称之为非常低的帧速率。
Like, it has what we call very low frame rate.
这就像在网上观看非常糟糕的GIF动画一样
This is like watching a really bad animated GIF online
它只有两个不同的框架。
that only has two different frames in it.
但看起来更像是他在走路，少得多
But it looks more like he's walking and much less
就像他在屏幕上来回滑动。
like he's gliding back and forth on the screen.
因此，我们实际上也可以从中获得一些乐趣。
So we can actually have some fun with this, too.
刮擦声。
Scratch support sounds.
因此，例如，这是我们之前听到的喵。
So, for instance, here's the meow we've heard before.
[喵]
[MEOW]
不过，如果我单击此处的小加号图标，则可以记录自己的内容。
I can record my own, though, if I click this little plus icon down here.
单击记录，并允许Scratch访问我的麦克风。
Click Record, and allow Scratch to access my microphone.
单击确定几次。
Click OK a couple of times.
开始了。
Here we go.
让我录制自己的声音。
Let me record my own voice.
哎哟。
Ouch.
好的。
All right.
那就是Ouch这个词的模样，至少在我发音的时候。
That's what the word Ouch looks like, at least when I pronounce it.
我可以在这里剪掉开头。
I can trim off the beginning here.
让我保存一下。
Let me save that.
我要给这张唱片起个名字，哦，
I'm going to give this recording a name, Ouch,
现在让我回到我的代码。
and now let me go back to my code.
在挡声板下，你知道吗？
And under the sound block, you know what?
让我继续说。
Let me go ahead and say this.
如果我触摸边缘，不仅要旋转180度。
If I'm touching the edge, not only do I want to turn 180 degrees.
现在，我可以使它更具趣味性。
Now I can kind of make this a little more playful.
电脑：哎呀。
COMPUTER: Ouch.
哎哟。
Ouch.
DAVID J MALAN：好的。
DAVID J MALAN: All right.
仍然不是很像猫，但同样，我们只是分层而已。
Still not very catlike, but again, we're just layering and layering.
这些方案的真正意义在于
And the takeaway here really is, as these programs
变得越来越复杂，在编写代码时目标永远不应该是
get more and more complicated, the goal should never be, when writing code,
无论是以Scratch还是C还是最终
whether it's in Scratch or C or eventually
此类或其他类别的Python，请尝试并开始尝试
Python in this class or others, to just start and try
实现你的整个愿景。
to implement your entire vision.
请注意，我从头开始编写的所有这些程序中，
Notice with every one of these programs that I wrote from scratch,
无双关语，我从小处开始，添加一两个或三个难题
no pun intended, did I start small and add one or two or three puzzle
从简单的东西发展到更复杂的东西。
pieces, building up from something simple to something more complex.
你知道吗？
And you know what?
我敢打赌，如果我们综合其中的一些想法，我们也可以做其他事情。
I bet if we synthesize some of these ideas, we can do yet other things too.
这是另一个例子，可能涉及抚摸猫。
Here's another example that involves, perhaps, petting a cat.
让我继续看一下该程序的内部。
Let me go ahead and see inside this program.
这个比较简单，但是目前还没有做任何事情。
This one's relatively simple, but it's not doing anything just yet.
我已经打了绿旗。
I already hit the green flag.
让我放大代码，也许你现在可以阅读我自己的代码
Let me Zoom in on the code, and you can, perhaps, now read my own code
我事先写的
that I wrote in advance.
猫永远在问这个问题，如果碰到鼠标指针则
The cat is forever asking the question, if touching mouse pointer then
播放声音直到完成。
play that sound meow until done.
好吧，即使程序正在运行，
Well, it would seem that even though the program is running,
它什么也没做。
it's not doing anything.
但它是。
But it is.
它正在等待某些事情发生。
It's waiting for something to happen.
所以让我将光标移到猫上，就像-
So let me move my cursor over the cat like--
[喵]
[MEOW]
- 这。
--this.
[喵]
[MEOW]
这样看来，如果我把它放在那儿，他会继续喵喵叫。
So it would seem, and if I leave it on there, he'll keep meowing.
这有点像是在抚摸猫的程序。
And it's kind of like a program that's petting a cat.
所以你可以想象现在有条件
And so you can imagine now having conditions
在使用布尔表达式确定的循环内部
inside of loops that are using Boolean expressions to decide
正是你想要做的事。
exactly what you want something to do.
更强大的是，即使使用Scratch之类的语言，我们也可以做到这一点。
And even more powerfully, even in a language like Scratch can we do this.
让我在这里打开有一个非常独特的树皮的海狮。
Let me open up the sea lion here, who has a very distinct bark.
但是他现在在演示具有多个脚本的程序。
But he's demonstrative now of a program that has multiple scripts.
因此，在这个Scratch项目中，我们不仅是一个程序，而且是两个。
So inside of this Scratch project now, we're not just one program but two.
请注意，这两者都在单击绿色标志时开始。
Notice both of which start when a green flag is clicked.
让我将它们都放在屏幕上。
And let me put them both onto the screen.
而且看起来更长。
And it looks longer.
但这仅仅是因为拼图不断增长，以适应彼此。
But that's just because the puzzle pieces are growing to fit each other.
让我们继续前进，点击“播放”。
Let's go ahead and hit Play on this.
玩
Play
[海狮吠叫]
[SEA LION BARKING]
注意，大约每秒钟，海狮都在吠叫。
Notice that every second or so, the sea lion is barking.
坦白说，这很快就令人讨厌。
And frankly, this gets annoying quickly.
但是我怎样才能阻止它呢？
But how can I stop it?
好吧，让我继续前进，在它仍然吠叫的时候在左边看。
Well, let me go ahead and look over here on the left while it's still barking.
请注意，海狮永远在问一个问题。
Notice the sea lion is forever asking a question.
如果静音等于假，则开始发出海狮的声音，请打个招呼两秒钟。
If muted equals false, start sounds sea lion, think hi hi hi for two seconds.
那么什么是静音的？
So what is muted?
好吧，回想起来，它的形状代表了
Well, the shape of it, recall, represents
一个变量，例如x或y或z，它只是保留信息的一种方式。
a variable, like x or y or z, which is just some way of retaining information.
所以这就像说，静音变量的值是否为false？
So this is like saying, is the value of the muted variable false?
如果是这样，你应该吠叫，因为如果它被错误静音，或者没有被静音，
If so, you should bark, because if it's false muted, if it's not muted,
继续播放海狮声。
go ahead and play the sea lion sound.
但是，我的上帝，让我们-在这里的右边，注意到还有另一个程序。
But my god, lets-- on the right here, notice there's another program.
单击绿色标志时，请永远提出问题。
When the green flag is clicked, forever ask the question.
如果按下空格键，则如果静音为true，
If the spacebar is pressed, then if muted is true,
将静音设置为false，否则将静音设置为true。
set muted to false, else set muted to true.
因此，右侧的程序将更改静音的值
So the program on the right is going to change the value of muted
从假到真或从真到假。
from false to true or true to false.
因为，天哪。
Because, my god.
我打了空格键
I've hit the space bar--
[海狮吠叫]
[SEA LION BARKING]
现在结束了。
And now it's over.
该程序仍在运行，但不再运行
The program is still running, but it's no longer
播放，因为静音现在为true而不是false。
playing because muted is now true and not false.
好吧，我们还能做什么？
Well, what else can we do?
事情很快就会变得很漂亮。
Things can get pretty fancy pretty quickly.
让我继续在这里创建另一个程序。
Let me go ahead and create one other program here.
我将继续进行，仅需两个方块即可完成。
And I'll go ahead and do one with just two blocks.
这个-让我再次进入扩展，这次是视频感测，
This one-- let me go into the extensions again, video sensing this time,
并注意有不同类型的启动程序的方法。
and notice there's different types of ways to start programs.
单击绿色标志时，并非每个程序都必须启动。
Not every program has to start when you click the green flag.
这里有一个类似的形状，但是这个是绿色的，
There's a similar shape here, but this one in green, that
表示视频运动大于10时。
says when video motion is greater than 10.
好像有10％的屏幕在移动。
Like 10% of the screen is moving.
让我将其增加到50％。
Let me increase that to 50%.
让我继续执行此操作。
And let me go ahead and do this.
让我继续前进，找到声音拼图。
Let me go ahead and find the sound puzzle piece.
播放声音直到完成。
Play sound meow until done.
所以现在我有一个两个程序块的程序。
So now I have a two block program.
当视频运动大于50时，播放声音直到结束。
When video motion is more than 50, play sound meow until done.
让我缩小。
Let me zoom out.
你会注意到我实际上在这里。
And you'll notice that I'm actually in the screen here.
让我离开舞台。
Let me move off stage.
现在什么都没有发生。
And now nothing is happening.
不过，让我去抚摸猫。
Let me go and pet the cat, though.
[喵]
[MEOW]
让我再做一次。
Let me do it again.
[喵]
[MEOW]
然后再次。
And again.
因此，它使用的是我计算机的摄像头-
So it's using my computer's camera--
[喵]
[MEOW]
-检测运动，然后执行该特定程序。
--detecting motion, and then executing that particular program.
同样，仅凭这些简单的构建块，
So again, with just these simple building blocks,
我们可以使越来越多的有趣事情发生吗？
can we get more and more interesting things to happen.
你知道吗？
And you know what?
我们甚至可以有多个精灵。
We can even have multiple sprites.
让我继续，打开一个老派游戏
Let me go ahead and open up an old school game
你可能在游泳池里玩过的游戏，
that you might have played in, like, a swimming pool, perhaps,
长大后，一个人大喊马可，另一个人大喊大叫
growing up, where one person yells out Marco and the other people
应该大吼大叫Polo。
are supposed to yell out Polo.
注意这里我们有一个带有两个精灵的程序。
Notice here we have a program with two sprites.
所以有两个木偶，一个橙色的木偶和一个蓝色的木偶。
So two puppets, an orange puppet and a blue puppet.
第一次在底部，
And down here at the bottom, for the very first time,
我们有两种不同的精灵编写程序的能力。
We have two different sprites' abilities to write programs.
所以现在选择了橙色木偶，
So right now the orange puppet is selected,
这意味着该程序位于左上角，
which means the program at top left here,
在这里，属于橙色木偶。
up here, belongs to the orange puppet.
而且橙色p已经被编程
And the orange puppet has been programmed
永远说，如果按下键盘的空格键，
to say forever, if the keyboard's space key is pressed,
然后说Marco两秒钟。
then say Marco for two seconds.
然后是新功能。
And then here's the new feature.
编程中有一种方法可以像进行一次程序交谈
There's a way in programming to have, like, one program talk
与另一个，或者在这种情况下，一个精灵与另一个交谈。
to another, or in this case, one sprite talk to another.
传递一种你在屏幕上看不到的秘密消息。
Sort of passing a secret message that you don't see on the screen.
但是一个程序可以听到另一个程序的声音。
But one program can hear from another.
这就是所谓的广播事件。
And that's called broadcasting an event.
这就是橙色木偶在做什么。
And that's what the orange puppet is doing.
如果我在这里单击蓝色木偶的图标，
If I click on the blue puppet's icon here,
他根本不会做太多事情。
he's not going to do very much at all.
但是，当单击绿色标志时，不执行任何操作，
But instead of doing anything when the green flag is clicked,
而不是在摄像机看到运动时做些什么，
instead of doing something when the camera sees motion,
相反，当他收到事件时，他要说Polo两秒钟。
he instead is going to, when he receives the event, say Polo for two seconds.
因此，在这种情况下，如果我立即点击“播放”，则什么也不会发生。
And so in this case, if I hit Play now, nothing happens yet.
但是当我按下空格键时，橙色表示马可，蓝色表示波罗。
But when I do hit the spacebar, orange says Marco, blue says Polo.
但是它们是独立编写的。
But they are written independently.
我已经为橙色编写了一个程序，为蓝色编写了一个程序，
I've written one program for orange, one program for blue,
他们正在以某种方式进行交流。
and they're somehow communicating.
说到交流，甚至还有
And speaking of communicating, there's even
这些天，借助互联网和云，你可以做更多的事情。
more things you can do these days thanks to the internet and the cloud.
让我继续，在这里打开另一个新画布。
Let me go ahead and open up one other new canvas here.
单击绿标时，很快给自己一个提示。
Very quickly give myself a when green flag clicked.
我先问同样的问题，问你叫什么名字
Let me go ahead and ask that same question before, ask what's your name
等一下
and wait.
但是现在让我进入这些扩展并让
But now let me go into these extensions and let
我找到了翻译扩展名，也就是
me find the translate extension, which is, again,
要使用云发送我在互联网上输入的任何内容
going to use the cloud to send whatever I type in out on the internet
然后返回响应，然后在此处在屏幕上说出来。
and get back a response, and then say it on the screen here.
因此，让我继续在屏幕上说些什么，例如打个招呼。
So let me go ahead and say something on the screen, like say hello.
但是我不想打招呼。
But I don't want to say hello.
我想回到“翻译”类别，
I want to go back to the Translate category,
我想继续翻译-
and I want to go ahead and translate--
你知道吗？
you know what?
我喜欢这个街区。
I like this block.
将某物翻译成另一种语言。
Translate something to another language.
但是，让我再次获得其中一个连接块，然后让我继续
But let me get one of those join blocks again, and let me go ahead
并输入单词hello，然后输入此人键入的姓名。
and join the word hello and then the name that the person has typed in.
为此，我再次需要答案块。
So to get that, I need the answer block again.
因此，我只是重新创建了较早版本的某些块。
So I'm just recreating some of our blocks from earlier.
并注意，在我刚刚这样做之前。
And notice, before I just did this.
我说了加入问候和回答的结果，尽管上次是逗号。
I said the result of joining hello and answer, albeit with a comma last time.
但是现在让我们开始吧。
But now let's do this.
让我接受join的输出，使其成为要翻译的输入。
Let me take the output of join, make it the input to translate.
让我在这里翻译成阿拉伯语。
Let me translate, say, to Arabic here.
让我拖放到say块中。
Let me drag and drop into the say block.
所以现在我们有两个输入要加入，连接的输出要去
So now we have two inputs going into join, join's output going
转化为翻译的输入，然后转化为翻译的输出。
into the input of translate, and the output of translate going into say.
但最终结果是，我将输入我的名字David并按Enter。
But the net result is going to be I'll type in my name David and hit Enter.
你好，大卫，现在是阿拉伯语。
Hello, David, now in Arabic.
全部归功于这些功能，条件和循环的原理，
All thanks to these principles of functions, conditions, and loops,
现在甚至加入了互联网。
and now even adding in the internet.
现在让我们考虑一下，最后再玩几局游戏。
Now let's consider finally, before we play a final couple of games.
总而言之，有一种方法甚至可以改善
In conclusion, there's a way to even improve
我们所做的很多事情的设计。
the design of a lot of what we've done.
实际上，让我回想一下刚才我们听到的那一声叫喊声。
In fact, let me go back just a moment to where we left off with that meowing.
在我们其中一个讨人喜欢的例子中，
And in one of our meowing examples, we had
看起来像这样的代码，我重复了三遍，
code that looked like this, where I repeated three times,
回想起来，我一次又一次地播放声音。
recall, and I played the sound meow again and again and again.
我当时认为这是更好的设计。
And I argued at the time that this was better designed.
为什么？
Why?
因为我不只是再次拖放同一块拼图
Because I didn't just drag and drop the same puzzle piece again
一遍又一遍。
and again and again.
我用了一个重复块，我丢掉了所有的冗余，
I used a repeat block, I threw away all of the redundancy,
而且我可以说一直很简单。
and I've arguably kept it simple.
我使用了一些更好的想法，但是代码更简单
I'm using some fancier ideas, but the code is simpler
而且现在拼图的数量更少了。
and it's fewer puzzle pieces now.
但事实证明，机会错失了
But it turns out that there's a missed opportunity
在这里应用计算机科学的另一个原理，
here to apply another principle of computer science,
这就是我们通常所说的抽象。
and this is what we would generally describe as abstraction.
抽象是解决问题的绝妙方法
Abstraction is this amazing problem solving
实际上只是一种奇特的表达方式
technique that's really just a fancy way of saying
让我们采用一个非常复杂的想法，或者一个稍微复杂的想法
let's take a very complicated idea, or a slightly complicated idea
并以某种方式简化它，我们都同意你可以实施它
and simplify it in such a way that we all agree that you can implement it
复杂的方式，但让我们现在规定一下
the complicated way, but let's now just stipulate
我们将在一个更简单的层面上考虑它。
that we're going to think about it as on a more simple level.
因此，让我继续看这个相同的程序。
So let me go over to this same program.
你知道吗？
And you know what?
奇怪的是，Scratch没想到会有喵叫声。
Scratch, curiously, did not anticipate having a meow block.
例如，有一个发言权区和一个思考区，但没有喵叫区。
Like, there is a say block and there's a think block, but there's no meow block.
这似乎适合于内置了猫的程序。
And that seems appropriate for a program where it comes with a cat built in.
因此，我们可以做到这一点。
So we can do this.
正如你可以创建自己的变量一样，请注意此处的左下方，
Just as you can create your own variables, notice at bottom left here,
你可以使用此粉红色类别创建自己的积木。
you can create your own blocks with this pink category.
如果我去这里，我将成为一个障碍
And if I go here, I'm going to make a block
我将这个叫作“喵喵”。
and I'm going to call this block meow.
很简单，我将单击“确定”。
And quite simply, I'm going to click OK.
现在注意，我得到了这个新玩具，上面写着喵。
Now notice I get this new puzzle piece that says define meow.
并且已经准备好将其他部分连接到它。
And it's ready to have other pieces connected to it.
我要如何定义喵？
How am I going to define meow?
我将继续将其拖到此处，因为我已经
I'm just going to go ahead and drag this over here, because I already
实施喵之前。
implemented meow before.
现在，请注意我左侧的内容。
And now, notice what I have on the left hand side.
因为我刚刚制作了这个自定义积木或拼图，
Because I've just made this custom block or puzzle piece,
我现在有一个名为喵的粉红色小块，就像Scratch附带的那样。
I now have a pink piece called meow, just as though it came with Scratch.
现在，令人着迷的是，我可以思考一下
And now what's compelling about this is that I can sort of think
视而不见，无所适从。
of this as out of sight, out of mind.
谁在乎喵的实现方式？
Who cares how meow is implemented?
我们知道我们早些时候实现了它。
We know we implemented it earlier.
现在让我们规定我们可以认为它的存在是理所当然的。
Let's now just stipulate that we can take for granted it exists.
而且，如果我现在放大新程序，那么从某种意义上讲它现在更具可读性。
And if I zoom in now on the new program, now it's more readable in some sense.
有点短。
It's a little shorter.
它的拼图块更少了。
It has a fewer puzzle piece.
但这也更具有自我描述性。
But it also is more self-descriptive.
我可以阅读我的代码。
I can read my code.
我可以看一下这段代码，然后说，好的，
I can look at this code and say, OK, it's
显然要重复三声喵叫声。
obviously going to repeat three times a meow block.
但是，让我们玩。
But let's play that.
[喵]
[MEOW]
没什么两样
It's no different.
[喵]
[MEOW]
二。
Two.
[喵]
[MEOW]
但是我敢打赌，我们可以进一步简化这一步骤，
But I bet we can simplify this one step further and make
它更加灵活。
it a little more flexible.
让我继续前进，然后在喵自定义块上单击鼠标右键或按住Control键单击。
Let me go ahead and right click or control click on the meow custom block.
让我在这里实际添加一个我们称为n的输入。
And let me actually add an input here that we'll call n.
让我添加一个带有时间的标签。
And let me just add a label that says times.
让我继续，然后单击“确定”。
And let me go ahead and click OK.
并请注意，我的拼图现在看起来有所不同。
And notice that my puzzle piece now looks different.
看起来更像是MIT的一些输入块
It looks more like some of MIT's blocks that take input
这些小小的白色椭圆形。
with these little white ovals.
而且，实际上，现在注意我能做什么。
And, in fact, now notice what I can do.
正如Scratch对我来说，我可以更改喵的定义，
I can change the definition of meow, as Scratch already has for me,
这样我现在可以在内部做更多的事情。
such that I can now do more inside.
让我实际上断开所有这些东西。
Let me actually disconnect all of this stuff.
让我将重复块移至喵本身的定义。
Let me move the repeat block to the definition of meow itself.
让我继续播放声音，然后在该重复块中等待，
Let me go ahead and play the sound and wait inside of that repeat block,
但请注意最后的这个小圆圈。
but notice this little circle around the end.
现在让我重复任意次数。
Let me just repeat an arbitrary number of times now.
我不必担心对3个或10个或其他任何东西进行硬编码。
I don't have to worry about hard coding three or 10 or anything else.
而现在，在你的视线范围之内，你无需再为此担心。
And now, out of sight, out of mind, don't have to worry about that anymore.
现在让我们简化一下这个越来越复杂的程序
Let's now just whittle down that increasingly complicated program
我们之前写的，实际上只有两个拼图。
that we wrote earlier into, really, just two puzzle pieces.
单击绿色标志时，肯定会发出三声喵叫。
When the green flag is clicked, meow, sure, three times.
我不必再知道或不在乎喵是如何实现的。
I don't have to know or care any more how meow is implemented.
我只需要知道有人为我做了，无论是麻省理工学院还是也许
I just need to know that someone did it for me, whether MIT or maybe
我自己，几分钟前。
myself, minutes ago.
我将再次点击播放。
I'll click play again.
[放映三遍]
[MEOWING THREE TIMES]
二三
Two, and three.
因此，现在我们有了抽象的实现。
And so now we have an implementation of abstraction.
采取一个有点复杂的想法，例如让猫咪喵喵叫，
Taking a somewhat complicated idea, like getting a cat to meow,
不用担心所谓的实施细节，
not worrying about the so-called implementation details,
并定义一个叫做喵的拼图或功能。
and just defining a puzzle piece or function called meow.
好吧，现在让我们一起考虑所有这些
Well, now let's take all of this together
并查看你过去的一些前任作品的一些创作。
and see some of the creations of some of your predecessors in past terms.
举例来说，这是几年前一位同学的故事
Here, for instance, is a sort of story that one of your classmates years ago
涉及姜饼故事。
made involving a gingerbread tale.
让我继续进行全屏播放，然后单击“播放”。
Let me go ahead and full screen this and click Play.
[音乐播放]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
现在你将看到我们已经有多个精灵，每个精灵
And you'll see now that we have multiple sprites already, each of which
有不同的服装，有人问我一个问题。
have different costumes, and I'm being asked a question.
你想要一个苹果吗？
Would you like an apple?
是还是不是。
Yes or no.
所以我不再被问到我的名字了。
So I'm no longer being asked my name.
我被问到任意问题。
I'm being asked arbitrary questions.
当然。
Sure.
我继续吃一个苹果。
Let me go ahead and have an apple.
我输入是，然后按Enter。
I type in yes and hit Enter.
注意运动。
Notice the movement.
我们以前看过运动。
We've seen movement before.
[刺耳的声音]
[CHOMPING SOUNDS]
[音乐播放]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
好的，不幸的是，这是在这个故事中做出的错误决定。
OK, unfortunately, that was the wrong decision to make in this story.
这样就可以了
So that's OK.
让我们重新开始。
Let's start it again.
红色停车标志。
Red stop sign.
[音乐播放]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
绿旗。
Green flag.
你好亲爱的，你想要一个苹果吗？
Hello dearie, would you like an apple?
不，让我们从这一课中学到东西。
No, let's learn from that lesson.
蛋糕听起来好多了。
Cupcake sounds much better.
这次我输入是。
I'll type yes this time.
再次注意该动议。
Notice, again, the motion.
所以那里有一些动画。
So there's some animation there.
它正在触碰另一个精灵。
It's touching the other sprite.
那也是不幸的。
That, too, was unfortunate.
让我们最后一次尝试这种艺术。
Let's try one last time with this art.
现在我们有一个苹果，没有。
And now we have an apple, no.
吸取了教训。
Learned a lesson.
蛋糕，不。
Cupcake, no.
吸取了教训。
Learned a lesson.
好的，现在让我们看看该循环会发生什么。
OK, now let's see what happens with that loop.
[咯咯地笑]
[CACKLING]
[尖叫]
[SCREAMING]
[刺耳的声音]
[CHOMPING SOUNDS]
好，惊喜结束。
OK, surprise ending.
但这就是说，通过采用这些循环构建块，
But this is all to say that by taking these building blocks of loops,
条件和功能，你可以开始制造东西吗
conditions, and functions, can you start to make things
更具互动性。
that are a little more interactive.
实际上，我本人几年前就做过-第一件事
In fact, I myself did something years ago-- the very first thing
我自己在Scratch中写的实际上是我在读研究生时
I myself wrote in Scratch was actually when I was in graduate school
并交叉注册了麻省理工学院的一门课程，教授
and cross-registered for a class at MIT, the professor for which
是Scratch本身的作者和创始人。
was the author of and the originator of Scratch itself.
让我继续全屏讨论并提出建议
And let me go ahead and full screen this and propose
我当时如何考虑解决当今的一个相当大的问题。
how I thought about solving, now, a fairly large problem back in the day.
尽量将掉落的垃圾拖入罐中。
Drag as much falling trash into the can as you can.
那么现在发生了什么呢？
So what's happening now?
屏幕上掉了一块垃圾。
A piece of trash is falling on the screen.
你会看到它从上到下移动，
You'll see that it's moving from the top to the bottom,
我们已经看到了这样的动画。
and we've seen animations like that.
但是请注意这一点。
But watch this.
我打赌使用条件和永远循环，
I bet using a condition and a forever loop,
我们可以使它成为可能。
we can make it possible to pick this up.
请注意，现在垃圾就像猫一样跟随着我的光标。
Notice now the trash is following my cursor, just like the cat was.
并请注意，如果碰触到其他垃圾桶可能会造成污染，
And notice if touching this other trash can sprite,
也许我们甚至可以让Oscar脱颖而出。
maybe we can even get Oscar to pop out of the can.
然后，他开始计算我的分数，从而使用一个变量，
And he, then, starts counting up my score, thereby using a variable,
实际上，随着更多的精灵或更多的垃圾掉落，
and indeed, as more sprites or more trash falls,
我可以继续以这种方式玩游戏。
I can continue to play a game in this way.
但是在这里，即使事情开始变得更快，
But here, too, even though things are starting to happen more quickly,
屏幕上还有更多，歌曲在后台播放，
there's more on the screen, the song is playing in the background,
所有这些都简化为基本的构建基块。
it all reduces to basic building blocks.
我不能强调太多。
And I can't emphasize enough.
当我几年前写第一个程序时，
When I wrote that first program years ago,
我没有实现你刚刚看到的内容。
I did not implement what you just saw.
我想我做的第一件事就是我在Google周围搜索
I think the very first thing I did was I googled around
并找到了芝麻街的路灯，然后将其放在屏幕上。
and found Sesame Street's street lamp and I put that on the screen.
那是第一个版本。
And that was sort of version one.
它什么也没做，但是看起来像我想要的。
It didn't do anything, but it looked like what I want.
然后我添加了垃圾桶。
Then I added the trash can.
然后，我想我编写了一个垃圾桶或一个精灵来掉落的程序。
Then I think I programmed one piece of trash or one sprite to fall.
所以我把猫变成了一块垃圾，然后
So I changed the cat to a piece of trash and then
我从上到下制作了动画。
I had it animate from top to bottom.
然后是第四或第五版，然后我添加了一个永久循环
Then version four or five, I then added a forever loop
以及检查鼠标按钮是否按下的条件，
and a condition that checks if the mouse button is down,
如果是这样，我可以跟随鼠标指针。
and if so, I have it follow the mouse pointer.
所以我遇到了一个大问题，并将其一点一点分解
So I took a big problem and broke it down bit by bit
分成更小的步骤。
into much smaller steps.
这与CS50自己的安德鲁·贝瑞（Andrew Berry）几年前采取的方法相同，
And this was the same approach that CS50's own Andrew Berry took years ago,
我们的一位教学研究员。
one of our teaching fellows.
我教CS50的第一年，创建了他自己的第一个Scratch
The very first year I taught CS50, created his very own first Scratch
我认为我今天会离开我们的项目。
project that I thought I'd leave us with here today.
这是他称为“下雨人”的程序。
This is a program that he called Raining Men.
它的音调可能很熟悉，我会
It might have a familiar tune, and I would
建议你在观看时考虑
propose that you consider, when watching this,
今天我们最后的Scratch程序，Andrew进行编程的方式
our final Scratch program today, how it is that Andrew went about programming
你所看到的一切。
everything that you see.
现在，安德鲁（Andrew）进入了现实世界，不再追求计算机科学，
Now Andrew went off into the real world and didn't pursue computer science,
本身。
per se.
他现在实际上是克利夫兰布朗队的总经理，
He's actually now the general manager for the Cleveland Browns,
这是一支美式橄榄球队。
which is an American football team.
但这也说明了你的基础是什么
But this, too, speaks to just what kind of foundation you
可以形成，而不论你打算的专业是什么，你可能的专业，
can form, irrespective of your intended major, your possible major,
毕竟，考虑到我们将要重点关注的许多想法
considering, after all, that a lot of the ideas we're going to focus on
这节课的最终目的是解决问题，
in this class are ultimately about problem solving,
编程只是交易的一种工具。
programming being just one tool for the trade.
而且的确，即使在体育界，
And, indeed, even within the world of sports,
如今在算法，分析等方面有很多机会，
are there so many opportunities nowadays for algorithms, for analysis,
进行视频模拟，以及安德鲁的许多世界
for video simulations thereof, and so many of Andrew's worlds
并且你的世界将不可避免地开始发生碰撞
and your worlds will invariably start to collide
当你开始构建自己的工具包时
as you begin to build up your own toolkit
和你自己的理解。
and your own understanding thereof.
因此，总而言之，我们将看看这个Andrews程序。
So in conclusion, we'll take a look at this, Andrews program.
同时，这是CS50，现在正在下雨。
In the meantime, this was CS50, and now it's raining men.
[音乐-“这是要训练的人”
[MUSIC - "IT'S RAINING MEN]
电脑：嗨。
COMPUTER: Hi.
你好。
Hi.
我们是你的天气女孩。
We're your weather girls.
嗯。
Uh huh.
并且我们有消息要给你。
And have we got news for you.
你最好听。
You better listen.
准备好所有孤单的女孩，把那些雨伞留在家中。
Get ready, all you lonely girls, and leave those umbrellas at home.
好的。
All right.
（正在唱歌）湿度在上升，气压计正在变低。
(SINGING) Humidity's rising, barometer's getting low.
哦。
Oh.
哦哦
Uh oh.
根据所有消息来源-
According to all sources--
现在有什么来源？
What sources now?
这条街是去的地方。
The street's the place to go.
“是因为今晚第一次，大约是十点半，
'Cause tonight for the first time, at just about half past 10,
这是历史上第一次要下雨的人！
for the first time in history it's gonna start raining men!
正在下雨的人，哈利路亚，正在下雨的人-
It's raining men, hallelujah, it's raining men--
[音乐播放]
[MUSIC PLAYING]